<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog del tecnólogo </title>
    <link>https://imfrom.github.io/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2018</rights>
    <updated>2018-08-16 23:56:45 -0500 CDT</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hunspell-en in Conflict With Hunspell en_US</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/hunspell-en-in-conflict-with-hunspell-en_us/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 23:56:45 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/hunspell-en-in-conflict-with-hunspell-en_us/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;On a different machine running the latest updates from Arch, pacman would give the error (and rightly so) that &lt;code&gt;hunspell-en and hunspell-en_US are in conflict&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;could not satisfy dependencies&lt;/code&gt; followed by &lt;code&gt;removing hunspell-en breaks dependency hunspell-en required by **antergos-common-meta**&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was of course never a problem on the other machine in which &lt;strong&gt;antergos-common-meta&lt;/strong&gt; was removed a while back. For the simple reason that the update related to anything &lt;strong&gt;hunspell&lt;/strong&gt; was in this particular case only for &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en_US&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-es_any&lt;/strong&gt; but not for, and this is important to note: &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en&lt;/strong&gt;. The latter includes all English dictionaries for US, UK, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the question is how to resolve this impeding conflict during the updates? Simply by skipping the package on pacman during the updates, or simply by deselecting the packages that belong to &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en_&lt;/strong&gt; on pamac (the gui version for pacman) for which the conflict exists in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; pacman -Su IgnorePkg=hunspell-en_US
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Pacman#Skip_package_from_being_upgraded&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Skip package from being upgraded&lt;/a&gt; on the Arch Wiki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By removing &lt;strong&gt;antergos-common-meta&lt;/strong&gt; the first time around on this particular
as I had done a few weeks ago on the other machine, made no difference. And
that&amp;rsquo;s the reason as to why the above is recommended. That is, by skipping the
packages in question that belong to &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en_US&lt;/strong&gt; for example first, and
then by proceeding with the updates normally seems to be the most reasonable
method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this is done, the next step would be to remove &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en&lt;/strong&gt; which would also remove &lt;strong&gt;antergos-common-meta&lt;/strong&gt; by which the latter package relies on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the next step would be in installing the libraries for &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en_US&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en_GB&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en_AU&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en_CA&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, in the latest installation ISO image, this issue with &lt;strong&gt;hunspell&lt;/strong&gt; and its dependencies has not been removed from the repositories that the installation media uses for the initial process. Which better explains as to why on the other machine which had the most recent Antergos installation, this problem was still present, whereas with the other machine in which I had removed &lt;strong&gt;antergos-common-meta&lt;/strong&gt; which removed &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-en&lt;/strong&gt; - the one that bundles all dictionaries for the English language - was never experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Setup Network Printer Ip Address Port Number</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/setup-network-printer-ip-address-port-number/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 01:31:19 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/setup-network-printer-ip-address-port-number/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Setting up a network printer seems not only problematic on Arch based systems, but also on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter also gave me the proverbial run for the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after I thought that the network printer had be configured correctly, errors such as &lt;code&gt;there was a problem processing document&lt;/code&gt; after printing a test page, or simply the error stating that &lt;code&gt;the printer may not be connected&lt;/code&gt; assured me that the network printer was not being correctly identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ommon &lt;strong&gt;U&lt;/strong&gt;nix &lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;rinting &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;ervices or as its acronym that is better known for: CUPS, is without a doubt, the most reliable method to set up any printer, and especially those that depend upon a network to operate accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not the first time setting up a network printer through CUPS, but
contrary to the first time around when the printer was successfully configured
on the system, in which the ip address had to be specified, and the connection
port number of the socket was automatically picked up by CUPS, this time around
however, specifying the ip address by itself made no difference with further
configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The printer was still not recognized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I scoured Google for any relevant results that would help me troubleshoot the problem, but none of the results seemed to provide a definitive answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arch Linux Forums was one of the first indicators that this issue was beyond a driver problem and rather a misconfiguration with the network printer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the thread entitled &lt;em&gt;Printer setting cant find wireless printer&lt;/em&gt;, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?pid=1605184#p1605184&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reply provided&lt;/a&gt; gave a couple of hints as to where to begin to troubleshot the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your post is much too vague. What does your wireless printer advertise? You should be able to add it using its IP address in the CUPS interface like this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.3&#34;&gt;http://192.168.1.3&lt;/a&gt;. You need to replace 192.168.1.3 by the IP of your printer and http:// could be socket:// lpd:// or something else&amp;hellip; Maybe you also have to specify a port number like this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.3:9100&#34;&gt;http://192.168.1.3:9100&lt;/a&gt;. If you can setup the printer in another OS (for example Windows); you might be able to find these by examining the properties of the printer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with Windows however, is that Windows itself does not provide a simple port configuration method that would have allowed me to see the ip address and the port that was currently in use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time around CUPS had already specified the ip address and the connection for the socket. But everything else for even the location had already been noted. Furthermore, I double checked it against the settings for the wireless configuration of the printer. Not solely relying on whatever configuration the display showed but also by printing out right from the printer the specifics of the configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ventured out to get a glimpse through a Windows system that would allow me to double check the settings, I encountered though, an unforeseen &lt;code&gt;An error occurred during port configuration. This operation is not supported&lt;/code&gt; which prevented me any further from finding out about the ip address and port number configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/windows-port-error-configuration.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This however, was not expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this question that was brought up on the stackexchange network, the user asked &lt;a href=&#34;https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/140009/list-all-network-printers-including-ones-not-installed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;to list all network printers (including ones not installed)&lt;/a&gt; and although it hinted that the program &lt;strong&gt;lpstat&lt;/strong&gt; with the flag &lt;code&gt;-a&lt;/code&gt; was one that would undertake the task, as the user pointed out, this would not apply to those printers that have not been installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another command that would certainly come handy is &lt;code&gt;lpinfo -v&lt;/code&gt; but more than what it provided was therefore needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another thread entitled &lt;a href=&#34;https://superuser.com/questions/662418/how-do-i-get-the-name-of-a-network-printer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;linux - how do you get the name of a network printer&lt;/a&gt; one of the comments said that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I run the nmap command it never seems to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://superuser.com/questions/662418/how-do-i-get-the-name-of-a-network-printer#comment836711_662485&#34;&gt;https://superuser.com/questions/662418/how-do-i-get-the-name-of-a-network-printer#comment836711_662485&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which pretty much matches many of the issues that I have encountered with the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only workaround with this pervasive problem of a printer that depends solely on the network, is through some sort of initial setup performed namely through a Windows system that would point it out. So by confirming the correct ip address and port numbers of the printer, would be more than enough to specify it as such on the location of the CUPS for the printer in question. Until then, and just like a user on the Arch Forums said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that the criteria (&amp;ldquo;Network Printer&amp;rdquo;) is something that only makes sense to humans. Computer programs aren&amp;rsquo;t going to have a clear sense of that idea. You might try doing a network sweep for IP addresses that successfully connect on the JetDirect port (tcp/9100). The list is still likely to be incomplete in the case of non-JetDirect printers such as desktop printers shared over SMB. – Bratchley Jun 30 &amp;lsquo;14 at 18:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/140009/list-all-network-printers-including-ones-not-installed#comment226003_140009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;unix.stackexchange.com/questions/140009/list-all-network-printers-including-ones-not-installed#comment226003_140009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Directory Permissions Differ on Var Cache Pkgfile</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/directory-permissions-differ-on-var-cache-pkgfile/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 02:49:21 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/directory-permissions-differ-on-var-cache-pkgfile/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last updates through pacman the following message came up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; warning: directory permissions differ on /var/cache/pkgfile/
 filesystem: 775  package: 755
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to first understand why this came up in the first place is good to know that &lt;code&gt;pkgfile&lt;/code&gt; is a tool for searching files in the official repos. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Pkgfile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pkgfile - ArchLinux wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the question as to why the &lt;strong&gt;pkgfile&lt;/strong&gt; differs for the file system hierarchy and the package itself has come up before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/falconindy/pkgfile/issues/25&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; on Github dealt with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the thread, one of the users reported whether it was necessary for &lt;strong&gt;pkgfile&lt;/strong&gt; to create the directory if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this is not the case here, but upon closer look on the pacman log it could be seen that &lt;strong&gt;pkgconf&lt;/strong&gt; had just been upgraded&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; upgraded pkgconf (1.5.2-1 -&amp;gt; 1.5.3-1)
 warning: directory permissions differ on /var/cache/pkgfile/
 filesystem: 775  package: 755
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which suggests that right after the updates it didn&amp;rsquo;t recreate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand &lt;strong&gt;pkgconf&lt;/strong&gt; is according to the manual pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; pkgconf is a program which helps to configure compiler and
 linker flags for development libraries.  This allows build
 systems to detect other dependencies and use them with the
 system toolchain.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;see for example what the aforementioned &lt;a href=&#34;Github https://github.com/falconindy/pkgfile/issues/25#issuecomment-227413406&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; issue on Github&lt;/a&gt; said about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a quick Google search would return among many of the results, the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?pid=317732#p317732&#34;&gt;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?pid=317732#p317732&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=223190&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; which in turn redirected to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=218133&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With due credit to where credit is due, the following post from the Manjaro community explicitly said that it was a warning and not an error itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;xabbu 2018-06-10 21:39:39 UTC #4
directory permissions differ on &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This message is a warning and not an error. This is normally not a problem. It just says that the permissions of a folder in a package differ form the permissions of that folder on your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally this will not result in a problem, however you should change the permissions to the package defaults to avoid future problems. This message is shown every time you update this package if the permissions don’t match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your specific case, at the moment only root and members of the group locate have access to the mlocate folder. With the change to 755 everybody can access and read the content of that folder. This don’t necessary mean everybody has also read access to the files in that folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the package folder contains different permissions than your system folder can have several reasons. Often it is because the upstream source have changed permissions. Sometimes a developer does this on purpose. But sometimes this happens by mistake and is changed back with the next release. Also the Maintainer can change the permissions of files and folder in the build process.
And of course the user sometimes changes the permissions of a file or folder and forget about or does it to fix a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also please note (@jochen82 @farverio ), if you have a problem with something else start a new thread with your problem to get help with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another thread on the same Manjaro forums this came up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fhdk 2018-05-07 10:34:00 UTC #4
rrrsssttt:
directory permissions differ on /var/lib/samba/private/
filesystem: 755 package: 700
bill_t:
It means that the permissions of this directory must be set to 755 (or drwxr-xr-x).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually it means the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The filesystem is 755 when the package expects it to be 700.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the right thing to do is to set permissions as the package expects it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo chmod 700 /var/lib/samba/private/
rrrsssttt:
I want to clarify that I don’t believe I have ever touched that folder (I may have installed apps that have touched it, but I consciously never have)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to. It is probably a fix since the folder mentioned is named private and as such is a folder that samba uses for stuff like certificates, keys, private keys, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such folder is only accessible for the system service running samba and the service will presumably refuse to run if permissions is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try that with your .gnupg folder or the .ssh folder. If permissions is world readable you will get complaints from application and some even refuses to run unless only accessible by owner aka chmod 700 ~/.ssh -R as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;see &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/i-got-a-warning-after-running-the-latest-round-of-updates-im-confused-what-to-do-next/46651&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I get a warning after running the latest round of updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the user on the Manjaro Forum pointed out when he/she said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually it means the opposite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the directory permissions of the package in question in the file system with a &lt;code&gt;chmod 755&lt;/code&gt; would be the best course of action for this package permission issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the reason why it occurs in the first place, is due to the fact that the tool &lt;strong&gt;pkgfile&lt;/strong&gt; must have administrative privileges during installation/upgrade in order to continue. That is, writing, reading and executing. But once the update has finished it no longer is necessary to keep the same permissions than before. The package no longer needs to have access to the home of the user in question.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linux Market Share Pitfalls: data manipulation and non-existent ranking markers</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/linux-market-share-pitfalls/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 02:50:35 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/linux-market-share-pitfalls/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;A while ago someone whom I came across on a technical forum
was vouching so much for one of the most used/popular Linux
Distributions that he/she almost gave the impression of
fully endorsing the distro in question, without further
proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said that he/she stated it without further proof because
all distributions consist of several software which make up
the whole system. So it would be gullible to think that one
particular distro employs Free Software while clearly
stating that the rest of the license by which the distro
developers go aheaad and implement it, is - as a result - within the
framework of say for example, what the Free Software
Foundation accepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the case. Most Linux distros, and even more
those that are amongst the most popular, are not very clear
in their terms with the programs that the distro&amp;rsquo; s
developers include and consequently employ within it, for further mass
use. No distribution out there but only a handful of them do
this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem that the above presents to the adoption of the Free
Software license is that many of these distributions do not uphold
licenses as they should or simply because its developers have included
other elements such as firmware nonfree blobs, or have provided
ambiguously writing in the documentation, and have offered other
methods that have provided download venues which in turn officially
endorse nonfree programs. More information about this can be seen on
the article entitled &lt;em&gt;Explaining Why We Don&amp;rsquo;t Endorse Other Systems&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#nonfree&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;nonfreeref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; posted on the Free
Software Foundation website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the poor statements that this user was trying to make about one of
the most popular Linux distributions at the time, could no longer hold
valid together under the license for which the Free Software
Foundation stands upon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further info about this, one could visit the Free
Software Foundation to get a glimpse at what this is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to make matters even worse, the user who was trying to
make his silly point, brought up one if not the most
inaccurate and misleading source of Linux Market Share
measure rankings&amp;rsquo; markers out there, a website named
&lt;strong&gt;Distrowatch&lt;/strong&gt; that lists the most popular GNU/Linux
distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which takes me to the second rant about why the above cannot be taken as an
statistical absolute. For &lt;strong&gt;Distrowatch&lt;/strong&gt; is just a community driven, heavily
edited, bureaucratically biased reviewed epicenter which sits on the web  with
layers of html markup with a domain registration.  Let me emphasize once again
about its biased one sided view about the certain distros&amp;rsquo; Linux Market Share.
It is important to do so because it is almost and will always be imprecise to
measure the use of GNU/Linux distributions across the spectrum and compare
these - whether community or commercially based
- with many of the most heard- of Operating systems without reliable methods
  and just by a simple likes/preferences which in the end, is nothing more than
  a preconceived notion of what distro should and should not be on the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, Distrowatch statement is vague to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Stack Frames: A Look From Inside&lt;/em&gt;, its author
said that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each website has its own list of the most popular
distributions, updated on the basis of different criteria,
    hence with different results. To give one example,
    Linux Mint was the most popular distribution in
    2013 and in the first half of 2014 according to
    Distrowatch, but is ranked twelfth on the
    LinuxCounter and LWN.  &lt;a href=&#34;#stack&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;stackref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is important because the disparity on numbers when
all the distributions are compared across LinuxCounter
&lt;a href=&#34;#linuxcounter&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;linuxcounterref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
and LWN &lt;a href=&#34;#lwn&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;lwnref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
greatly differ from Distrowatch. The differences would
be much more profound if other websites would try to gather
these numbers as long as the list is not edited or
maintained by users who manipulate this data like in the case of
Distrowatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of the LWN site, the author of &lt;em&gt;Stack Frames: A
Look From Inside&lt;/em&gt;, was also on the err side and may have
made some subtle mistakes with the rankings of the distros.
This may be noted with some of the inconsistencies with the
top market share of the distros in use. That is,  the
chronologically order of the distributions as it was
reflected on the book and as the author pointed out, is
certainly troublesome.  The list on LWN is enumerated
alphabetically and it does not necessarily offers numbers
that could be used as a better counter/measurement
tool/indicator/predictor in this case. It does show,
however, the mainstream distributions or the ones that have
been around the longest
- commercial and community based - in the computing world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading about this pervasive problem with the market share
of GNU/Linux programs, and the distributions that include
these programs in addition to the share of these
distributions along with the biases that are taking place in
community sites such as Distrowatch, the author of a blog on
the Medium blogging service platform said that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I notice when they have an axe to grind against a
particular distribution bad reviews are allowed to flourish
but if I or others submit positive reviews they tend to get
ignored and there are more than a handful of distributions
where I have noticed that trend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what it&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate is that such misleading bits of information
occur nowadays, especially within the culture of the GNU/Linux
Operating system which even includes its kernel without which the vast
GNU software accomplishes nothing.  But most importantly listing the
so called &amp;lsquo;popular&amp;rsquo; when most of the &amp;lsquo;popular&amp;rsquo; distributions do not
even adhere to the Free Software Foundation standards guidelines of
Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author in that blog stated that Distrowatch is biased towards
free-as-in-beer distributions, but I would disagree because I do think
the bias is there regardless whether is more commercially oriented by
which the distribution in question implements free software or not. It
is the case that community driven do not necessarily implement the
licenses any better than commercially based distros. But it makes no
difference in the case of this website. . The users responsible to
update the counter list for the distros or in this case the distro
that should appear on the top are undoubtedly misinforming real market
share data without further repercussions. And by the looks of it, what
matters is the ad-driven commercially source of income that derives
from this data manipulation to the owner of Distrowatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea whether this GNU/Linux user that commented about how
that Linux distro fared in comparison with the rest, was aware of
these facts, but Distrowatch in general has been around for a while
and I wonder whether they have affected the objective and the goal
overall of the Free Software Foundation Guidelines.&lt;br /&gt;
No doubt that the reviews need further revision but they&amp;rsquo;re
doing so while promoting their own, without regard for the
particular distro and whether this is community-driven or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Linux Distribution Timeline offers in turn the progress
of the Linux Distributions and although is a great project
on its own right, it does not undertake where all the sites
have fallen short to accomplish this difficult task of having a
better Market Share Model that tackles the Linux world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website for this project is located at &lt;a
href=&#34;http://futurist.se/gldt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;futurist.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;- &lt;a name=&#34;nonfree&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/distros/common-distros.en.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Explaining Why We Don&amp;rsquo;t Endorse Other Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#nonfreeref&#34;&gt;&amp;crarr;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;-&lt;a name=&#34;stack&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=YZIoDQAAQBAJ&#34;
target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stack Frames: A Look From Inside&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#stackref&#34;&gt;&amp;crarr;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;-&lt;a name=&#34;linuxcounter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linuxcounter.net/statistics/distributions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.linuxcounter.net/statistics/distributions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#linuxcounterref&#34;&gt;&amp;crarr;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;-&lt;a name=&#34;lwn&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lwn.net/Distributions&#34;
target=&#34;_blan&#34;&gt;lwn.net/Distributions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#lwnref&#34;&gt;&amp;crarr;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Gscan2pdf Sane Start Invalid Argument</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/gscan2pdf-sane-start-invalid-argument/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 23:48:49 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/gscan2pdf-sane-start-invalid-argument/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Antergos wins here. Manjaro could have done better but it
didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who would want to avoid having to go through the
hassle of reinstalling and testing sane drivers under Arch
Linux should look no further. The comparison wasn&amp;rsquo;t done
between all the Arch Linux based distributions, but Antergos
is the clear winner here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No Desktop Environment under Manjaro worked to have this
driver functioning as it should have been functioning. And
this is after trying Manjaro KDE, Manjaro XFCE, the most
popular of the bunch. Didn&amp;rsquo;t try it with GNOME and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t
going to waste my time with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps later versions would fared better, but this time
around it didn&amp;rsquo;t deliver what it was expected from this
distribution. The main issue had to with the &lt;code&gt;invalid
argument&lt;/code&gt; error message from programs such as &lt;strong&gt;gscan2pdf&lt;/strong&gt;
and also from &lt;strong&gt;xsane&lt;/strong&gt; and in identifying and picking up
the right device other than the infamous &lt;code&gt;Noname integrated
camera&lt;/code&gt; that it would only identify from the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/Screenshot_2018-07-24_23-45-03.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reinstalling both Manjaro KDE and the XFCE version the
problem continued in identifying the correct device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/Screenshot_2018-07-25_00-17-57.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Antergos it worked without a major issue and for that
reason alone I recommend this distribution over Manjaro.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Pamac Runs Post Install Hooks but Fails to Install New Updates</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/pamac-runs-post-install-hooks-but-fails-to-install-new-updates/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 21:31:56 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/pamac-runs-post-install-hooks-but-fails-to-install-new-updates/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The GUI version of &lt;strong&gt;pacman&lt;/strong&gt; which runs under Antergos
installed the scheduled updates as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as soon as new updates were found it just failed to
install them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, after running the post installation hooks, it
found a new update for one of the programs. But this time
however, it failed to even initialized the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it could have been relatively simple to circumvent
the problem by seeing through &lt;strong&gt;pacman&lt;/strong&gt; itself what the error
was, but just closing the &lt;strong&gt;pamac&lt;/strong&gt; application, seemed all
that was needed to have the problem fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after, the GUI version &lt;strong&gt;pamac&lt;/strong&gt; had no further issues
to install the updates accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is is just a reminder not to fully rely on
&lt;strong&gt;pamac&lt;/strong&gt; and used the main package manager for any Arch
based distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Could Not Satisfy Dependencies Hunspell Antergos Common Meta</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/could-not-satisfy-dependencies-hunspell-antergos-common-meta/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:12:54 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/could-not-satisfy-dependencies-hunspell-antergos-common-meta/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems as if &lt;strong&gt;antergos-common-meta&lt;/strong&gt; has been removed
from some of the repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest updates by using pamac or even pacman returned
the &lt;em&gt;could not satisfy dependency&lt;/em&gt; error that was required
in this case for the hunspell Spanish dictionary &lt;strong&gt;hunspell-es&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/Screenshot_2018-07-17_23-51-16.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus by removing &lt;strong&gt;antergos-common-meta&lt;/strong&gt; or whatever was left
of it, resolved the problem, it seems that the Antergos
community haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to resolve some of these issues
that keep coming up every now and then with the
distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Google search about this problem returned, among the
results some posts like &lt;a
href=&#34;https://forum.antergos.com/topic/10303/cant-solve-dependencies-hunspell&#34;
target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t solve dependencies hunspell&lt;/a&gt; which
summarised the same error message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike other occasions, I didn&amp;rsquo;t read about this particular issue this time, The reason for not following up on it is due to the fact that a few days ago a dependency problem had appeared about a &lt;code&gt;..libso.2&lt;/code&gt; (I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the name of the file, this time around), but it was a file that needed to be removed before successfully continuing with the updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully the Antergos developers will be able to correct some
of these inconsistencies in an otherwise great distribution
that is based on Arch, before a greater share of users who are
fond of Arch, not only migrate to it, but fully adopt it as
the main OS in their systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then some of these errors and dependency satisfaction
from the packages would have to be resolved manually by the
end-users on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Installing Pacman Breaks Dependency</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/installing-pacman-breaks-dependency/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 06:34:49 -0400</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/installing-pacman-breaks-dependency/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Running one of the usual updates from the pamac gui package, returned&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; pamac: installing pacman (5.1.0-1) breaks dependency ‘pacman&amp;lt;5.1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that any package on the list with a dependency must be
unchecked before continuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later I checked the antergos forum to see if there was any solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/pacman-cant-install-breaks-dependency.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suggested workaround was to run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; pacman -Syyu -d  --nodeps
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following commit apparently introduced the issue in the first
place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git.archlinux.org/svntogit/packages.git/commit/?id=e9272fcb3289f875b1a14222fb17f9185274107f&#34;&gt;https://git.archlinux.org/svntogit/packages.git/commit/?id=e9272fcb3289f875b1a14222fb17f9185274107f&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Antergos Keyboard Selection During Installation</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/antergos-keyboard-selection-during-installation/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 08:49:17 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/antergos-keyboard-selection-during-installation/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the drawbacks during the installation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://antergos.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Antergos Linux&lt;/a&gt; was in identifying the keyboard layout option that was previously selected during the media installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result only the default variant was being used after installing the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to identify the problem by going to the X window system xorg configuration file &lt;code&gt;/etc/X11/xorg.d/00-keyboard.conf&lt;/code&gt; and noticing that the &lt;strong&gt;XkbLayout&lt;/strong&gt; variant was not being properly identified as originally intended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, only one of the options had been specified correctly on the &lt;code&gt;00-keyboard.conf&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found odd, is that on another system, which is by the way, running the same xfce environment from Antergos, the same problem was not encountered. On the other system, only one (1) variant was used, and it had correctly identified the layout twice, but on the system which after installing the Antergos media, loaded the incorrect values, two (2) variants were set accordingly, but only one (1) layout option was identified. In my case &lt;strong&gt;us&lt;/strong&gt; had been been identified once, whereas with the former no issues pertaining to this problem occurred in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the wiki &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Keyboard_configuration_in_Xorg#Using_X_configuration_files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using X configuration files wiki&lt;/a&gt; recommends, not to modify any of the settings manually, but let instead &lt;strong&gt;localectl&lt;/strong&gt; handle it. &lt;a href=&#34;#sample&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;sampleref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/localectl-usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it comes handy when there is even an example that illustrates the process by using the correct parameters. For something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/00-keyboard-sample.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then something like the following &lt;a href=&#34;#localectl&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;localectlref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, based on the previous example, suffices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/localectl-sample-usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the values as deemed applicable to the desired customization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;sample&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Keyboard_configuration_in_Xorg#Using_X_configuration_files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using X Configuration files 00-keyboard.conf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#sampleref&#34;&gt; &amp;#x21A9;&amp;#xFE0E;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;localectl&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Keyboard_configuration_in_Xorg#Using_localectl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using localectl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#localectlref&#34;&gt; &amp;#x21A9;&amp;#xFE0E;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Antergos Grub Selection</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/antergos-grub-selection/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 08:38:47 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/antergos-grub-selection/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;During the installation of Antergos, there was an option to install the Linux LTS kernel along with the default latest stable version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it was installed appropriately, the option to select the other kernel, could not be seen from the Grub selection window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is even after running the usual mkinitcpio -p &lt;linux kernel&gt; that loads the modules and other dependencies accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s good to remember that Grub configuration file though, resides on the /boot/default directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With sudo privileges, access the file at /boot/default/grub first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therein, and lying at the bottom of the configuration file, one can find the:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  # Uncomment to make GRUB remember the last selection. This requires to
  # set &#39;GRUB_DEFAULT=saved&#39; above.
  #GRUB_SAVEDEFAULT=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One could uncomment the GRUB_SAVEDEFAULT=&amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; so the grub configuration file ‘remembers’ the selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, and right on the top of the file the default chosen selection can be specified by modifying the value of 0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;# GRUB boot loader configuration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GRUB_DEFAULT=0
To a 2 or 3 for the desired kernel. Which in my case, and if the LTS kernel is to be loaded instead, matched the kernel itself and the fallback for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By going this route, it no longer is necessary in specifying during the system startup, the desired kernel that one chooses to be loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember after making any changes to grub, to update the configuration file by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;grub-mkconfig -o /boot/grub/grub.cfg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info about this, visit the wiki:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/GRUB/Tips_and_tricks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GRUB/Tips and tricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Udisks2 Udiskie Fares Better Than Ntfs 3g</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/udisks2-udiskie-fares-better-than-ntfs-3g/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 08:45:02 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/udisks2-udiskie-fares-better-than-ntfs-3g/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It is my opinion, based mostly not on what I’ve read, but instead on what I’ve encountered during the handling of a failed hard disk, that the disk volume mounting utility udisks2 fares better than say, ntfs-3g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite possibly there could be many improvements with this software, and there is no doubt about it, but considering wear-and-tear conditions of the disk, among other considerations, and, as long as udisks2 is run without an interruption, no other mounting options utility that is currently available may be able to improve its overall performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If time is not a constraint, and the program is allowed to run on its own, udisks2 fares relatively better on previously loaded Windows OS partitions than any other. Of this I can attest without a doubt. The utility has been able to eventually access corrupted filesystems that would have been rendered unrecoverable otherwise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-futher-info-and-configuration-visit-the-wiki&#34;&gt;For futher info and configuration, visit the wiki:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Udisks#Mount_to_.2Fmedia_.28udisks2.29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount to /media (udisks2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Udisks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Udisks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/NTFS-3G&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ntfs-3g Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/coldfix/udiskie/wiki/Usage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;udiskie on github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Metadata Irreversible</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/metadata-irreversible/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 04:13:37 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/metadata-irreversible/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the easiest ways to remove all metadata from a file, is by invoking &lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/metadata-irreversible/#exiftool&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;refexiftool&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ exiftool -all= &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this has the inconvenience of providing a security risk by reversing it as well with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ exiftool -pdf-update:all= &amp;lt;file&amp;gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which pretty much inserts the metadata back into the file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/exiftool-reversible-metadata-warning.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the author of &lt;strong&gt;exiftool&lt;/strong&gt; this can be circumvented by issuing &lt;code&gt;qpdf --linearize &amp;lt;file.in&amp;gt; &amp;lt;file.out&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. For further info about this see:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://owl.phy.queensu.ca/~phil/exiftool/TagNames/PDF.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF tags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/pdftags-linearized.png&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;exiftool&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sno.phy.queensu.ca/~phil/exiftool/exiftool_pod.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;exiftool man pages&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/metadata-irreversible/#refexiftool&#34;&gt;_↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Manjaro Kde Plasma Dolphin Mtp Cant Open File</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-kde-plasma-dolphin-mtp-cant-open-file/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 13:26:25 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-kde-plasma-dolphin-mtp-cant-open-file/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MTP&lt;/strong&gt; implementation runs on most desktop environments without a problem. Except on KDE where it has had several problems in identifying and initializing a simple file from any of the devices that have been connected to the system, mainly through the USB port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really a shame that although Plasma KDE fairly supports Bluetooth protocol better than the rest of other desktop environments, it largely fails with both gwenview and its default Dolphin manager to open up files directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried in a great many occasions to slither out many of these KDE errors by falsely attributing it to my lack of knowledge on its usage. But I can’t deny any longer that the system either works or it doesn’t. And one should no longer have to wait who-knows-how-long-and-when, before updates smother out its deficiencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I have tried to look up for the issue elsewhere such as as in &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=177028&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mtp mount issues in KDE/Dolphin&lt;/a&gt;, but many of the suggestions have not worked so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas with KDE, to my amazement - because at this point of its developmental phase, one would think that it should perform better and not worse - the problems all range from mild to critical, while &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt; on the other hand, these unexpected malfunctions and sudden out-of-the-blue crashes do occur but at a lesser degree, and when one of these errors undermines the stability, the errors do not necessarily affect the overall functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I experienced and spoke at somewhat length about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-kde-plasma-error-unknown-application-folder/&#34;&gt;manjaro kde error unknown application&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of recent Bluetooth vulnerabilities that have happened,&lt;a href=&#34;#blue&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;blueref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  and the history behind it in which several authors have researched the issue, it makes no sense to have a whole interface that handles this protocol better than most environments and yet fails when the to-be-expected approach to handle it differently or by using the right terminology, handling it without bluetooth at all in light of everything that has happened with it, by going directly through the use of the mtp protocol that takes care of it. And the mtp is supported without a major flaw in &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Gnome&lt;/strong&gt;, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further reading about &lt;strong&gt;MTP&lt;/strong&gt;, is advised to visit the formidable wiki from Arch Linux at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/MTP&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that kio-extras is a dependency of Kde’s dolphin file manager, which apparently is partly responsible for the &lt;code&gt;failed to initlialize&lt;/code&gt; error, but whichever is to be blamed in this regard, matters for as long as the user finds the KDE environment worthy to be used. In my case perhaps, the same opinion that for so long I’ve had of the software, has notably changed amid these recent problems: first with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-kde-plasma-error-unknown-application-folder/&#34;&gt;manjaro kde error unknown application instance as highlighted earlier&lt;/a&gt;, and now with the bluetooth problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps is worthy to revisit this desktop environment, but for now, it is in my opinion that there are better options out there from which to choose from, before having to put up with the inconsistencies and failures that have rendered the systems I have been running lately, useless in more than one occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mobile.slashdot.org/story/17/09/12/2030213/blueborne-vulnerabilities-impact-over-5-billion-bluetooth-enabled-devices&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blueborne vulnerabilities impact devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#blueref&#34;&gt;_↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Manjaro Kde Plasma Error Unknown Application Folder</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-kde-plasma-error-unknown-application-folder/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 13:28:52 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-kde-plasma-error-unknown-application-folder/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s apparently a foolish idea to login as root from a file manager on Plasma KDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was exactly what caused a number of problems, and among them, most notably, that I could not get past the login screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, little did it matter that I installed any of the other display managers available and removed the current in use from the command line. I was still unable to get past the login screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it wasn’t just the usual &lt;code&gt;login failed&lt;/code&gt; which indicates the wrong username and/or password. This was exactly the opposite, as after inputting the password for the system, since &lt;code&gt;login automatically&lt;/code&gt; was disabled, the screen would fall back as if it loading the kernel again, and then without further ado, back into the login screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feedback loop process was endless. I couldn’t but scourge on Google for some sort of information regarding the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first queries to Google was with the terms &lt;strong&gt;plasma kde fails to startx&lt;/strong&gt;, although I knew that the last element of the query was not the most accurate. For one, because the &lt;strong&gt;X server&lt;/strong&gt; was somehow running, or else how could I have a login screen in the first place. But almost unsurprisingly, the first result from Google was from the Arch Linux forum entitled &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=193286&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cannot start plasma 5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to follow one of the recommendations and modify the last line to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; exec startkde
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/change-xinitrc-for-kde-plasma-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but it made no difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps on other desktop environments the change on &lt;strong&gt;.xinitrc&lt;/strong&gt; was a success, but at least on Manjaro Plasma KDE, all of it was failing and I was not able to get past the login screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the suggestion to modify the &lt;strong&gt;.xinitrc&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt; desktop environment have proven to succeed without any major problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See for example &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=147721&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Can’t get past the login screen&lt;/a&gt;, where modifying the &lt;code&gt;.xinitrc&lt;/code&gt; was more than enough to get it started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/change-xinitrc-for-xfce-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point it was futile to modify any further the &lt;strong&gt;.xinitrc&lt;/strong&gt; initialization file when moments before I had restarted the system, an error related to Plasma KDE had popped up on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/plasma-error-window.png&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple more errors from the main file manager Dolphin showed for example the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/user-xbel-kde-plasma.png&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And also&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/kio_applicationsrc-error.png&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, after the infamous error with the &lt;strong&gt;kio_applicationsrc&lt;/strong&gt;, I very well knew that the culprit of it all occurred when trying to login as root to Plasma from the Dolphin file manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, after giving up the have Manjaro KDE running on the system, I found a few posts that spoke about logging in as root on the Plasma environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the same post that for example was highlighted earlier, there is useful information as why running as root as KDE is altogether discouraged:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/dont-run-as-root-on-kde.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Errors During Hugo Git</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/errors-during-hugo-git/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 15:56:07 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/errors-during-hugo-git/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last setup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, I was faced again with the sometimes difficult handling of submodules. This was of course after the corresponding configuration for the &lt;code&gt;user.name&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;user.email&lt;/code&gt; had already been set accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next error which dealt with the git submodule was that it already existed in the index. Which made me look it up on Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the first results that came up after my query, was the following from the stackoverflow site at the StackExchange Network, entitled &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/12898278/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Issue with adding common code as git submodule: “already exists in the index”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer that has been widely accepted included as a solution having to invoke the &lt;code&gt;git rm --cached projectfolder&lt;/code&gt; on the tree of the folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After issuing it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git rm --cached .git/public 
 fatal: pathspec &#39;.git/public&#39; did not match any files
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which clearly led me nowhere, I noticed that further implementing correctly the command would require a few more steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The command &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt; indicated that origin did not appear to be a git repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git push origin master
 fatal: &#39;origin&#39; does not appear to be a git repository
 fatal: Could not read from remote repository.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only after I invoked the &lt;code&gt;git rm -rf public&lt;/code&gt; which seemed to fix the problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git rm -rf public/
 Migrating git directory of &#39;public&#39; from
 &#39;/public/.git&#39; to
 &#39;/.git/modules/public&#39;
 rm &#39;public&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seemed to at least tell me that the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder had been removed. So apparently the &lt;code&gt;--cached&lt;/code&gt; flag did nothing in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, by using the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;tab&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; key for autocompletion, right after the directories, I invoked &lt;code&gt;git rm -rf .git/modules&lt;/code&gt;, which showed the number of possibilities as shown below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git rm -rf .git/modules/
 about                        index.html
 config.toml                  index.xml
 config.yaml                  js
 content                      page
 &#34;content                     post
 css                          &#34;post
 deploy.sh                    sitemap.xml
 .gitmodules                  static
 google4417fd3500b3c667.html  &#34;static
 images                       tags
 &#34;images                      themes
 img                          topics
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, I completed the &lt;code&gt;git rm -rf&lt;/code&gt; with the corresponding &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git rm -rf .git/modules/public/
 fatal: pathspec &#39;.git/modules/public/&#39; did not match any files
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which unfortunately again, came back with the &lt;strong&gt;fatal: pathspec&lt;/strong&gt; error from before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What worked, was to have the option &lt;code&gt;--cached&lt;/code&gt;, to be implemented right after &lt;code&gt;git rm&lt;/code&gt; only recursively with the &lt;strong&gt;.gitmodules&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git rm --cached .git
 .git/        .gitmodules  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which finally after tab completion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git rm --cached .gitmodules 
 rm &#39;.gitmodules&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it seems the &lt;code&gt;git rm --cached&lt;/code&gt; worked with the &lt;strong&gt;.gitmodules&lt;/strong&gt;, but it did not succeed with the &lt;strong&gt;.git/modules/public&lt;/strong&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only after I invoked the Unix command &lt;code&gt;rm -rf&lt;/code&gt; under the &lt;strong&gt;.git&lt;/strong&gt; directory, that the problem was finally resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ rm -rf .git/modules/public/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After it, the submodule was added again with the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; git submodule add -b master &amp;lt;name of static repository&amp;gt; public
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As shown below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git submodule add -b master https://github.com/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;static repository&amp;gt; public
 Cloning into &#39;/public&#39;...
 remote: Counting objects: 2075, done.
 remote: Compressing objects: 100% (91/91), done.
 remote: Total 2075 (delta 74), reused 114 (delta 31), pack-reused 1907
 Receiving objects: 100% (2075/2075), 4.06 MiB | 2.17 MiB/s, done.
 Resolving deltas: 100% (1247/1247), done.

 $ 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The step-by-step instructions by simply issuing &lt;code&gt;rm -rf public&lt;/code&gt; as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tutorial to have Hugo running on Github&lt;/a&gt; suggested, did not work in this case, for the simple reason that the &lt;strong&gt;git repository&lt;/strong&gt; was cloned during the initial setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;.git/modules/public&lt;/strong&gt; already existed as a result. So it had to be removed by issuing &lt;strong&gt;rm -rf .git/modules/public&lt;/strong&gt; before setting up again the submodule remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/hugo-step-by-step-instructions.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Screen Locker Broken Manjaro Kde</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/screen-locker-broken-manjaro-kde/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 13:58:20 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/screen-locker-broken-manjaro-kde/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;While updating a fresh installation of Manjaro KDE, the screen locked.
Apparently the default settings for the system, enabled this behavior without
further ado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of this problem, the surprising part came afterward when the updates that were being downloaded, suddenly crashed the system. This led to the nonetheless bothersome problem of &lt;code&gt;modules.devname not found&lt;/code&gt; error followed by the no more troublesome error &lt;code&gt;you are now being dropped into an emergency shell&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sh can&#39;t access tty; job control turned off&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have at the time a live media to access the system. Although I knew the that the sudden crashing during the download of updates , was one of the problems underlying the &lt;code&gt;modules.devname not found&lt;/code&gt; error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick google searched returned  &lt;a href=&#34;https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/355689/manjaro-fails-to-boot-modules-devname-not-found-then-unknown-disk-uuid-error&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manjaro fails to boot, modules.devname not found&lt;/a&gt; a result which provided an answer that pointed to access the system with Manjaro’s own &lt;code&gt;mhwd-chroot&lt;/code&gt; command to access the emergency shell. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php/Restore_the_GRUB_Bootloader#Chroot_into_your_existing_Manjaro_Installation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chroot into your existing Manjaro Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/mhwd-chroot-steps.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as the already mentioned answer on the unix.stackexchange.com site suggested, it was necessary to reload the image again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/chroot-answer-mkinitcpio.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Configuring Kakoune Kakrc</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/configuring-kakoune-kakrc/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 12:50:38 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/configuring-kakoune-kakrc/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Configuring the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kakoune text editor&lt;/a&gt; initialization file has been nothing short of a chore, as it requires the path environment to be correctly set, before any changes on the &lt;code&gt;kakrc&lt;/code&gt; take ahold of the settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the tutorial suggests, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune#configuration-autoloading&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Configuration and autoloading&lt;/a&gt;, if it is launched with the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; switch, kakoune will source the &lt;code&gt;../share/kak/kakrc&lt;/code&gt;, but on a unrelated issue but nonetheless relevant about the correct location for the initialization file, the developer clearly stated that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kakrc file in share is Kakounes init script, it is not intended to be user edited. It is actually that script that will load your user configuration in ~/.config/kak/kakrc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/dont-use-share-kakrc.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune/issues/1102&#34;
target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;clang completion #1102&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, it is necessary to set the environment first on any Unix system. The command &lt;code&gt;setenv&lt;/code&gt; is used for the &lt;strong&gt;csh&lt;/strong&gt; shell, whereas in &lt;strong&gt;bash&lt;/strong&gt;, this is accomplished through the &lt;code&gt;export&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out whether for example, &lt;code&gt;XDG_CONFIG_HOME&lt;/code&gt; was set, is necessary to invoke on the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; printenv XDG_CONFIG_HOME
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which if it does not return a value, the environment has not been set yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set the environment across sessions, note it accordingly on your &lt;code&gt;bashrc&lt;/code&gt; file with the &lt;code&gt;export&lt;/code&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; export XDG_CONFIG_HOME=$HOME/.config
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;create a directory &lt;strong&gt;kak&lt;/strong&gt; under that environment, and further create your init file &lt;strong&gt;kakrc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the available settings will be available without further modifications. That is, some of the commands that are loaded by not using a &lt;code&gt;kakrc&lt;/code&gt; file, will not have to be further tweaked with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; colorscheme &amp;lt;tab completion&amp;gt; &amp;lt;name of theme&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;can be identified without a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are, however, a handful of those that would have to be further tweaked with, in order to load the &lt;strong&gt;kakrc&lt;/strong&gt; init file correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example, &lt;code&gt;autowrap-enable&lt;/code&gt;, which normally applies soft wrap manipulation to the lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the developer,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;autowrapping is provided by the autowrap.kak script (which should be loaded by default), enable it for a buffer with the autowrap-enable command, that you probably want to put in a hook (for example if you want to always enable autowrap, add hook global WinCreate .* %{ autowrap-enable } in your kakrc. the autowrap_column option controls the column on which to autowrap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune/issues/419&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Noob questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/autowrap-kakrc.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further customizations to map certain keys are also necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, to map the &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt; backslash key to say the &lt;code&gt;;&lt;/code&gt; semicolon., it’s imperative to precede the *&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt; key with the &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; percent sign and further enclose the &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt; backslash key within curly brackets &lt;code&gt;{}&lt;/code&gt;, so the final code would be something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; map buffer insert %{\} &#39;;&#39; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;of course, if the settings are desirable to be loaded globally, then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; map global insert %{\} &#39;;&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;needs to be specified accordingly on the initialization file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See for example this issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune/issues/419&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;can’t map to backslash&lt;/a&gt;, which touched upon the problem, and further linked &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune/issues/1049&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune/issues/1049&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune/issues/1221&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mawww/kakoune/issues/1221&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s certainly two-fold that by specifying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; map buffer insert &#39;;&#39; \ 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the behavior to have the &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt; inserted, is easily accomplished, as shown on the example above, but the same is not true, by having the same characters inversed within the strings, that would yield the correct results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for example whereas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; map buffer insert &#39;;&#39; \ 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is correct, a simple &lt;code&gt;map buffer insert &#39;\&#39; ;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;throws an error with the message &lt;code&gt;parse error: unterminated string &#39;...&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s therefore necessary to have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; map buffer insert %{;} \
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the same is true if one were to &lt;code&gt;map buffer insert &#39;\&#39; %{;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one of the methods that would work across buffers, is to have such characters enclosed within curly brackets and further preceded by the &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; sign&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; map buffer insert %{\} %{;} 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; map buffer insert %{;} %{\} 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Network Has Been Disconnected Manjaro Kde Xfce</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/network-has-been-disconnected-manjaro-kde-xfce/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 13:41:54 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/network-has-been-disconnected-manjaro-kde-xfce/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For some unknown reason, I was getting the message &lt;code&gt;network has been disconnected&lt;/code&gt; even on connections that have been previously used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the post entitled &lt;strong&gt;NetworkManager doesn’t automatically ask for a password for new network&lt;/strong&gt;, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=142066&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;see this post on bbs.archlinux.org&lt;/a&gt; in my case the connection was used many times before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dependency problem that has plagued this bug seemed to make a comeback on a most of Manjaro desktop environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing, or better put, reinstalling it with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; yaourt -S gnome-keyring
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;seemed to resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same problem hasn’t been experienced on Antergos distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Mounting a Windows Hard Drive on Arch Linux</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/mounting-a-windows-hard-drive-on-arch-linux/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 13:40:27 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/mounting-a-windows-hard-drive-on-arch-linux/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;After following some of the advice on &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/NTFS-3G&#34;&gt;ntfs-3g arch linux&lt;/a&gt; entry which described the procedure to mount a windows system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;lsblk -f&lt;/code&gt; call on the filesystem returned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; sdb                                                         
 ├─sdb1 vfat   SYSTEM   
 ├─sdb2 ntfs   Recovery 
 ├─sdb3                 
 ├─sdb4 ntfs   OS       
 └─sdb5 ntfs   Restore  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was after &lt;strong&gt;sdb4&lt;/strong&gt; in this case. So I invoked on the command line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ ntfs-3g /dev/sdb4 /mnt/fat/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which returned the message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Unprivileged user can not mount NTFS block devices using the external FUSE
 library. Either mount the volume as root, or rebuild NTFS-3G with integrated
 FUSE support and make it setuid root. Please see more information at
 http://tuxera.com/community/ntfs-3g-faq/#unprivileged
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with sudo privileges I invoked it again, but this time around the more precise error message that &lt;em&gt;Input/output error NTFS is inconsistent&lt;/em&gt; was returned on the terminal. The entire message was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; ntfs_attr_pread_i: ntfs_pread failed: Input/output error
 Failed to read of MFT, mft=391080 count=1 br=-1: Input/output error
 Falling back to read-only mount because the NTFS partition is in an
 unsafe state. Please resume and shutdown Windows fully (no hibernation
 or fast restarting.)
 ntfs_attr_pread_i: ntfs_pread failed: Input/output error
 Failed to read NTFS $Bitmap: Input/output error
 NTFS is either inconsistent, or there is a hardware fault, or it&#39;s a
 SoftRAID/FakeRAID hardware. In the first case run chkdsk /f on Windows
 then reboot into Windows twice. The usage of the /f parameter is very
 important! If the device is a SoftRAID/FakeRAID then first activate
 it
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to invoke it with &lt;code&gt;mount&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;ntfs-3g&lt;/code&gt;, then it would have mounted it without a setback&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ sudo mount -t ntfs-3g /dev/sdb4 /mnt/fat
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;successfully mounted it and I was able to access the files on that hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Git Committing by User Name Config</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/git-committing-by-user-name-config/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:01:35 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/git-committing-by-user-name-config/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had to set up again the local branches through git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An error that was not uncommon came up on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; *** Please tell me who you are.

 Run

   git config --global user.email &#34;you@example.com&#34;
   git config --global user.name &#34;Your Name&#34;

 to set your account&#39;s default identity.
 Omit --global to set the identity only in this repository.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time around it was done through configuring a &lt;code&gt;user.name&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;user.email&lt;/code&gt; on git itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came to memory that the last time I was setting it up on a different system by pulling the sources from the remote branch, this configuration was never used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An answer on stackoverflow reminded me that this was indeed the case the last time I had done it. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/17713604&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; instead of doing a git pull you can do a git fetch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; git fetch
 git reset --hard origin/master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if the error from &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; with the &lt;strong&gt;please tell me who you are&lt;/strong&gt; comes up after an ssh key is granted, as it was posted on this other thread entitled &lt;em&gt;Git-please tell me who you are error when using ssh key&lt;/em&gt;, the best alternative is to specify the &lt;code&gt;--global&lt;/code&gt; option from &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; as it posted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/42335651&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; run git config –global user.email - git config –global user.name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if the option to have a &lt;code&gt;--global&lt;/code&gt; configuration is not desirable, then the removal of this &lt;code&gt;.gitconfig&lt;/code&gt; file may be accomplished through &lt;strong&gt;git&lt;/strong&gt; again by issuing &lt;code&gt;git config --global --unset-all user.name&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;git config --global --unset-all user.email&lt;/code&gt; from the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the website that aims at answering questions about the ubuntu distributiion, there are more examples with this purpose. See for example &lt;a href=&#34;https://askubuntu.com/questions/206449/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; git config global file - remove settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important part about it lies on the command &lt;strong&gt;–unset-all&lt;/strong&gt;, even though the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com//a/282550&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;  answer&lt;/a&gt; which pointed at it was not the accepted solution in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details about the config-file for &lt;strong&gt;git&lt;/strong&gt; it is recommended to read the manual &lt;strong&gt;man git-config&lt;/strong&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Npm Warn Saveerror Enonent During Uninstall</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/npm-warn-saveerror-enonent-during-uninstall/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 13:44:21 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/npm-warn-saveerror-enonent-during-uninstall/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently tried a few utility programs through &lt;strong&gt;npm&lt;/strong&gt; javascript manager. For further info see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Npm_(software)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Npm package manager&lt;/a&gt; on Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after trying them, I noticed that the output compilation was not what I had expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, or so it seems, that by default the programs end up on &lt;code&gt;/usr/lib/node_modules&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept one of the programs which I found it handy and very convenient. But I just wanted to remove the rest from the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But lo and behold. The removal outcome for the programs was not what I had expected either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;npm&lt;/strong&gt; threw errors even with sudo privileges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; npm WARN enoent ENOENT: no such file or directory, open &#39;package.json&#39;
 npm WARN c No description
 npm WARN c No repository field.
 npm WARN c No README data
 npm WARN c No license field.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was easily resolved by issuing the flag &lt;code&gt;-g&lt;/code&gt; (get) for a successful uninstall. So that was &lt;code&gt;npm uninstall &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; -g&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later I checked on &lt;code&gt;/usr/lib/node_modules&lt;/code&gt;, to make sure the program was no longer on the system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Manjaro Xfce Qpdfview Problem With Qt5ct Unable to Load Plugin in First Attempt</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-xfce-qpdfview-problem-with-qt5ct-unable-to-load-plugin-in-first-attempt/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 03:52:43 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-xfce-qpdfview-problem-with-qt5ct-unable-to-load-plugin-in-first-attempt/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I currently have two (2) identical - or that’s what it seemed like - &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt; environments on two (2) different hardware systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always keep at hand a list of viewers and if there is any problem removing those to be found unnecessarily large or extremely light to the point of rendering them useless, I tend to check the Arch Wiki at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/list_of_applications&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;List of Applications&lt;/a&gt; for a refresher on what’s available at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always found useful, more or less two (2), or three (3) of them, among them, with a quick copy-paste from the Arch Wiki:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gv — Graphical user interface for the Ghostscript interpreter that allows to view and navigate through PostScript and PDF documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ePDFView — Free lightweight PDF document viewer using the Poppler and GTK+ libraries. Development stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;qpdfview — Tabbed document viewer. It uses Poppler for PDF support, libspectre for PS support, DjVuLibre for DjVu support, CUPS for printing support and the Qt toolkit for its interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter, strangely enough, was behaving differently on one of the &lt;strong&gt;manjaro xfce&lt;/strong&gt; systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick google search turned pretty much nothing, related to this issue I was having: namely, the adjustment and consequent resizing for the Settings Window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/manjaro-xfce-qpdfview-settings-box-wrong.png&#34; width=&#34;680px&#34; height=&#34;450px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the image above, I was unable to get to the bottom of the window whereto I could’ve specified &lt;strong&gt;to cancel&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;apply&lt;/strong&gt; the changes to take effect via a GUI. What use is a GUI if one can’t access the main settings of the program?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This took me to the wrong path in trying to modify the settings upon which the &lt;strong&gt;Dialog box&lt;/strong&gt; depended on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The settings for &lt;code&gt;qpdfview.conf&lt;/code&gt; were found right under the &lt;code&gt;.conf/qpdfview/&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To no avail I tried to change the settings for the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; settingsDialogSize=@Size(488 803)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the &lt;strong&gt;qpdfview.conf&lt;/strong&gt; file, but every single time I did so, even after changing the above size to other feasible settings, the settings window loaded the default and preconfigured values for it, rendering any change I had made earlier such as modifying the values for that &lt;strong&gt;settingsDialogSize&lt;/strong&gt; onto the configuration file,  obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I gave up tweaking around with the &lt;code&gt;qpdfview.conf&lt;/code&gt; file. Even after removing this file, removing &lt;strong&gt;qpdfview&lt;/strong&gt; along with all poppler libraries from the system, reinstalling the program again, logging out of the system, and restarting, and logging right back in, the problem still persisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The settings window remained, remained useless for the most part - and from a GUI’s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I could have just pressed the &lt;strong&gt;carriage&lt;/strong&gt; return key on the keyboard to apply the changes, or for that matter the &lt;strong&gt;escape&lt;/strong&gt; key to discard any changes, but this was just besides the point, since it defeated the purpose of having GUI applications running. I needed it to be operational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried another venue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that every single time that the program &lt;strong&gt;qpdfview&lt;/strong&gt; was invoked from the command line, several errors appeared, including the most significant of the lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; qt5ct: using qt5ct plugin
 qt5ct: D-Bus global menu: no
 Could not load plug-in in first attempt: &#34;&#34;
 &#34;The shared library was not found.&#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the second of these messages was self-explanatory. The libraries upon which qpdfview relied upon, were not recognizing or finding the plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick search on google later regarding &lt;strong&gt;qt5ct&lt;/strong&gt; did not provide a satisfactory explanation behind the &lt;strong&gt;qpdfview&lt;/strong&gt; problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read some of the visual methods in adjusting the settings for &lt;strong&gt;qt&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcsuggest.com/qt5ct-change-qt5-application-style/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Change Qt5 application style with qt5ct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started &lt;strong&gt;qt5ct&lt;/strong&gt;, and I noticed that the default settings for the window was to have &lt;strong&gt;gtk2&lt;/strong&gt; as the style to be loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then right after I had changed it to one of the other values, I had high expectations that the changes would improve the dimensions of the dialog box settings for &lt;strong&gt;qpdfview&lt;/strong&gt;. But I was wrong. It made everything worse off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally had to tweak around with the problem directly through the &lt;code&gt;qt5ct.conf&lt;/code&gt; file by changing the style field. Only then the problem with &lt;strong&gt;qpdfview&lt;/strong&gt; was resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; [Appearance]
 color_scheme_path=
 custom_palette=true
 icon_theme=Vertex-Maia
 style=gtk2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The style value was modified to &lt;strong&gt;Breeze&lt;/strong&gt;, I saved the file and exited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;qt5ct.conf&lt;/strong&gt; file should have on the Appearance the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; [Appearance]
 color_scheme_path=
 custom_palette=true
 icon_theme=Vertex-Maia
 style=Breeze
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right after making the changes - not even a logout was required - &lt;strong&gt;qpdfview&lt;/strong&gt; dialog box dimensions were working and definitely manageable. The only glitch - if it may be rightfully called as such - was an apparent back-to-back unwanted behavior in which the whole window for the settings, was not clearly visible, but one quick maximizing drag-around-movement maneuver, fixed the annoyance once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/qpdfview-correct-settings-dialog-box-1.png&#34; width=&#34;680&#34; height=&#34;450&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Manjaro Xfce Bluetooth Problem</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-xfce-bluetooth-problem/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 13:32:01 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-xfce-bluetooth-problem/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth recognition - at least on Manjaro Xfce - has been erratic and inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For no clear reason the LTS kernel and even a newer kernel have identified the hardware, while it has failed to do so in a great many occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the tweaks included reinstalling &lt;code&gt;bluez&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;bluez-firmware&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;bluez-libs&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;bluez-tools&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;bluez-utils&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the drawing room and back again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bluetooth adapters were not being recognized however. And after logging out and back into the session, and even after &lt;code&gt;sudo /sbin/shutdown -r now&lt;/code&gt;, nothing seemed to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day - to my surprise - I booted the system and it picked the bluetooth adapters without a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of a comment on the manjaro forum thread entitled &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/bluetooth-adapters-app-not-opening-bluetooth-manager-bluez-failed/4367/19&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bluetooth adapters app not opening Bluetooth Manager&lt;/a&gt; in which one of the participants said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth support in Linux is always troublesome, even in Windows, smartphone, etc. So yeah, I think staying away from bluetooth related hardwares if you want a trouble free experience. Wireless hardwares nowadays are going towards a dedicated receiver way to handle wireless connection and that’s a better approach. Just my two cents &lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-xfce-bluetooth-problem/#blueref&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;blueref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to agree with him on that regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the desktop environment &lt;strong&gt;KDE&lt;/strong&gt; hasn’t - I ran it for a short while and perhaps my feedback is worthless of consideration on that regard - given me the same problems than the current configuration under &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I never thought that the problems would persist even after the installation of a newer kernel. That is perhaps the main reason which has been drifting me away from &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt; until further notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while &lt;strong&gt;KDE&lt;/strong&gt;-fanboys have come up with the slogan that &lt;em&gt;it grows on you&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt; is perhaps a more GNU/Linux-centric configurable environment than the former. I still enjoy tweaking with its features even though its less polished than Plasma &lt;strong&gt;KDE&lt;/strong&gt;. There is no question about this. &lt;strong&gt;KDE&lt;/strong&gt; aims at the latest hardware, while &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on the rest. I’ve never tried to benchmark its memory and CPU consumption, but I’m almost certain it fairs much better than &lt;strong&gt;KDE&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt; will be a daily desktop environment driver running the main programs on which my workflow depends upon, it’s a question of time and how well it will handle them without a major setback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/bluetooth-adapters-app-not-opening-bluetooth-manager-bluez-failed/4367/19&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;bluetooth adapters not opening bluetooth-manager-bluez-failed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#blueref&#34;&gt;_↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Urxvt Copy Paste Tweaking</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/urxvt-copy-paste-tweaking/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 14:07:29 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/urxvt-copy-paste-tweaking/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t read the &lt;code&gt;man&lt;/code&gt; pages enough to figure out some of the parameters that play an important behavior for the full functionality of the mighty &lt;strong&gt;urxvt&lt;/strong&gt;, and it was not until I read a post - which was more of a comment on the thread entitled &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=221108&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;right click paste in urxvt terminal&lt;/a&gt; on the archlinux.org forum - when I realized that by the combination of &lt;strong&gt;ctrl&lt;/strong&gt; and right mouse click would copy and paste the selected text on the X window system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/2017-08-18-ctrl-right-click-urxvt.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the above to work without a problem under &lt;strong&gt;xclip&lt;/strong&gt; so far.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Urxvt Background Tweaking</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/urxvt-background-tweaking/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 14:05:19 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/urxvt-background-tweaking/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never bothered with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/rxvt-unicode&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;urxvt&lt;/a&gt; in the past. Perhaps was the way that dealt with the default glyph, which discouraged me from using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later I found that the above was easily answered here at &lt;a href=&#34;https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/81746/how-can-i-get-better-looking-fonts-in-my-term&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;how can I get better looking fonts in my terminal (urxvt)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, the simple fact that I had to modify it directly on &lt;code&gt;.Xresources&lt;/code&gt;, stopped me from doing all the necessary modifications to accomplish it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I also found the excellent script &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/majutsushi/urxvt-font-size&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;urxvt-font-size&lt;/a&gt; which allows changing the font size on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one problem I faced with this magnificent terminal was the handling of the background color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignorant I was of the fact that although &lt;code&gt;.Xresources&lt;/code&gt; is the responsible source to change the background, one must specify it, and not expect to interpret the default values of &lt;code&gt;xterm&lt;/code&gt;, a different terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until a post which was replying to a thread opened on the Arch\Linux forums entitled &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?pid=957150#p957150&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rxvt-unicode font color too dark&lt;/a&gt; which pretty much condensed what I was after, and made me feel more stupid afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/2017-08-18-karol-answer.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Setup Remote and Master Branches Before Updating Hugo</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/setup-remote-and-master-branches-before-updating-hugo/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 14:00:51 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/setup-remote-and-master-branches-before-updating-hugo/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I had to set remote and master branches on a different machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The methods included setting it up through the &lt;code&gt;git pull&lt;/code&gt; command. By going tis route, both the master and remote branches were consequently set and configured without a major inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, although I tried to replicate the same method above, I faced problems that included among many other errors, the infamous &lt;code&gt;error: src refspec master does not match any. error: failed to push some refs to &#39;origin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t going to go through the poor method of setting up a new site and copy-paste among other files, the &lt;code&gt;posts&lt;/code&gt; folder, the &lt;code&gt;theme&lt;/code&gt;, the &lt;code&gt;config&lt;/code&gt; files, and any other modification I had previously committed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site was being generated without a mishap, so I knew it had to do with the no less complicated &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;, since some of the errors, like the above, were clearly describing that &lt;code&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt; did not match the one from the remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the necessary steps are as follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1-Remove with &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; all leftovers from the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder with &lt;code&gt;git rm -rf public&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2-Remove the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder itself with &lt;code&gt;rm -rf.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3-Add the static site as a submodule to the master with &lt;code&gt;git submodule add -b master &amp;lt;git@github.com:&amp;lt;USERNAME&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;USERNAME&amp;gt;.github.io.git public&amp;gt;.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that should be more than enough to have it working in no time. Push your changes and update it accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Xfce Carpalx Layout</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/xfce-carpalx-layout/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 12:09:38 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/xfce-carpalx-layout/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to add the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mkweb.bcgsc.ca/carpalx/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;carpalx&lt;/a&gt; layout to X window system on GNU/Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desktop environment Plasma KDE does not have that problem. One could easily add it from the &lt;strong&gt;Input Devices&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;settings&lt;/strong&gt; of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If however, one is running &lt;strong&gt;Xfce&lt;/strong&gt;, things are not as straightforward as one would like them to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of this post, one can find the zip archive where the &lt;em&gt;carpax.xkb&lt;/em&gt; file resides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unzip the contents and open up the README.txt to have an idea of what to copy. But there are two (2) things/caveats to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One shouldn’t modify the &lt;em&gt;symbols/us&lt;/em&gt; file as it was suggested by the author&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No need to follow Step 3 by loading the layout with setxkbmap carpalx. For one thing it will not load the default variant of the layout.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m just posting the following as it currently appears on the README.txt file provided by the author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;installation-instructions&#34;&gt;INSTALLATION INSTRUCTIONS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copy carpalx.xkb to your XKB symbols directory (path my differ slightly)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ cp carpalx.xkb /usr/share/X11/xkb/symbols/carpalx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the following lines to /usr/share/X11/xkb/symbols.dir&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-dp—– a——- carpalx(qgmlwb)
–p—– a——- carpalx(qgmlwy)
–p—– a——- carpalx(qfmlwy)
–p—– a——- carpalx(qwkrfy)
–p—– a——- carpalx(qwyrfm)
–p—– a——- carpalx(tnwmlc)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now it should be possible to load the layouts with, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ setxkbmap carpalx                            # defaults to QGMLWB
$ setxkbmap -layout carpalx -variant qwkrfy    # to select other variants&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following files should also be updated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/usr/share/X11/xkb/rules/xorg.lst
/usr/share/X11/xkb/rules/xorg.xml&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;one-better-way-to-accomplish-it&#34;&gt;One better way to accomplish it:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;instructions-to-follow&#34;&gt;Instructions to follow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copy indeed carpalx.xkb to the XKB symbols directory with sudo privileges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ cp carpalx.xkb /usr/share/X11/xkb/symbols/carpalx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;strong&gt;/usr/share/X11/xkb/rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ cd /usr/share/X11/xkb/rules&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once there and with sudo privileges again open &lt;strong&gt;evdev.lst&lt;/strong&gt;. Add it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/edit-evdevlst.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the file &lt;strong&gt;edev.xml&lt;/strong&gt; and add the variant to the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/edit-evdevxml.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;strong&gt;Keyboard Settings&lt;/strong&gt; of the &lt;strong&gt;xfce&lt;/strong&gt; graphical environment and add it. It will show on the list as shown in the following image:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/xfce carpalx layout · blog del tecnólogo_files/add-carpalx.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloadable zip files:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mkweb.bcgsc.ca/carpalx/distribution/carpalx-x11.zip&#34;&gt;http://mkweb.bcgsc.ca/carpalx/distribution/carpalx-x11.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Manjaro Announces Password Weakness en Los Instaladores De Dvd/usb</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-announces-password-weakness-en-los-instaladores-de-dvd_usb/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 13:20:54 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-announces-password-weakness-en-los-instaladores-de-dvd_usb/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Recientemente en &lt;a href=&#34;http://distrowatch.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DistroWatch&lt;/a&gt; se publicó el anuncio del lanzamiento de la última versión de &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manjaro&lt;/a&gt; que incluye importantes actualizaciones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/2017-06-27-manjaro-announcement.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entre estas actualizaciones se encuentran las nuevas versiones de los instaladores gráficos tanto como &lt;strong&gt;thus&lt;/strong&gt; al igual que &lt;strong&gt;calamares&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;También se anuncia la fragilidad en la generación de la contraseña o la clave que tanto el programa &lt;strong&gt;thus&lt;/strong&gt; como &lt;strong&gt;calamares&lt;/strong&gt; emplean durante el proceso de instalación a través tanto del ya mencionado &lt;strong&gt;thus&lt;/strong&gt; o de &lt;strong&gt;calamares&lt;/strong&gt; que en hashtag con modo predecible se utiliza durante la creación de estas contraseñas. &lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-announces-password-weakness/#shadow&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;shadowref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Las versiones más recientes de &lt;strong&gt;thus&lt;/strong&gt; y de &lt;strong&gt;calamares&lt;/strong&gt; no están afectadas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por lo tanto es recomendable acceder al fichero que contiene estos errores y verificar si tu sistema está afectado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primero antes que todo para recordarnos quiénes somos - si por casualidad se nos olvidó el nombre de usuario, en la terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ whoami
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Que nos imprime el nombre de usuario&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una vez con esta información y con privilegios de usuario, es decir, mediante &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;  accede al fichero &lt;code&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/code&gt; mediante tu editor de texto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desde la terminal selecciona uno de los siguientes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; sudo emacs /etc/shadow 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; sudo vim /etc/shadow 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; SUDO_EDITOR=kate sudoedit /etc/shadow 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingresa tu contraseña de usuario después para leer el fichero y verificar si la contraseña necesita ser regenerada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La penúltima línea del fichero comienza con tu nombre de usuario, es decir, con el valor que &lt;code&gt;whoami&lt;/code&gt; devolvió anteriormente, seguido de &lt;code&gt;$6$&lt;/code&gt;, pero si la penúltima línea del fichero &lt;code&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/code&gt; contiene tu nombre de usuario encerrado por dos signos &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt;, entonces lo más probable es que necesitas crear nuevas contraseñas. Recuerda que tu nombre de usuario es el valor que &lt;code&gt;whoami&lt;/code&gt; devolvió en la terminal. Este nombre de usuario no debe estar encerrado por los dos signos &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si necesitas corregir este error, y desde la terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ passwd 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cuyo comando invocará&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ Current password:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Necesitas ingresar tu actual contraseña, y después especificar tu nueva contraseña, lo cual generará el hashtag correcto en el fichero &lt;code&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antes de cerrar el archivo &lt;code&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/code&gt; que tenía estos errores, asegúrate que &lt;strong&gt;root&lt;/strong&gt; no tiene los mismos problemas que el usuario. En este caso, &lt;strong&gt;root&lt;/strong&gt; es la primera línea del archivo &lt;code&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/code&gt; lo cual es más fácil de revisar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por ejemplo, si aparece:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; root: $6$ 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;y después de ello aparece tu &lt;code&gt;whoami&lt;/code&gt; encerrado entre dos signos &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt;, también tienes que arreglarlo con la generación de una &lt;code&gt;passwd&lt;/code&gt; para &lt;strong&gt;root&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para acceder &lt;strong&gt;root&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ sudo su
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;que por consiguiente estarás ejerciendo todos los comandos con los máximos privilegios desde la terminal. Si por casualidad no requiere la contraseña porque por ejemplo, haz accedido anteriormente con privilegios administrativos que utilizaste para cambiar la clave de usuario, asegúrate en ingresar en la línea de comando el ya mencionado:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; # passwd 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;el cual invocará que especifiques tu contraseña de root. Acto seguido a ello ingresa tu nueva contraseña.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el caso de &lt;strong&gt;shadow-&lt;/strong&gt; no hay que hacer ninguna modificación. Es decir, el fichero &lt;strong&gt;shadow-&lt;/strong&gt; que es seguido de un diptongo, es un archivo de copia del original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para más detalles acerca de esto vea la página en &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/manjaro-installers-password-weakness/26322&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manjaro installers - password weakness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Gcc Multilib in Conflict With Gcc During Manjaro Upgrade</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/gcc-multilib-in-conflict-with-gcc-during-manjaro-upgrade/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 04:04:38 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/gcc-multilib-in-conflict-with-gcc-during-manjaro-upgrade/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;During the latest Manjaro upgrade, a conflict of packages already installed on the system, was preventing to proceed with the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick search on Google returned among the results, a post which had recently been opened on the archlinux forum with the title &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=226723&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;conflict with gcc-libs and gcc-libs-multilib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the conflict of packages on my system, was not the same conflict than the ones reported on the archlinux forum such as with the package gcc-fortran, it was clear as a user suggested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gcc-*-multilib is all or nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my system, querying the database for &lt;code&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;pacman -Qs gcc&lt;/code&gt; returned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/2017-06-08-gcc-gcc-multilib-conflict.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was missing &lt;strong&gt;gcc-libs&lt;/strong&gt;, while &lt;strong&gt;gcc-libs-multilib&lt;/strong&gt; was installed instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick &lt;code&gt;pacman -Ss gcc&lt;/code&gt; query - see &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/pacman#Querying_package_databases&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;archlinux wiki - Querying package databases&lt;/a&gt; would show the &lt;strong&gt;gcc-multilib&lt;/strong&gt; and its accompanying files for the package &lt;strong&gt;gcc-libs-multilib&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/2017-06-08-gcc-multilib-gcc-libs-multilib.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I ended up doing to avoid the conflict and proceed with the upgrade as scheduled, was to remove the old version of &lt;strong&gt;gcc&lt;/strong&gt; - 6.8 if I’m not mistaken now, although I can always check the revision history for the exact number of the package I had at the time - and reinstall &lt;strong&gt;gcc&lt;/strong&gt;. I figured to do that, since for one, I had to install the newest version for the compiler anyways, and once done with the system upgrade, then the package &lt;strong&gt;gcc&lt;/strong&gt; would be reinstalled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final &lt;code&gt;pacman -Qs gcc&lt;/code&gt; would return:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/2017-06-08-pacman-qs-gcc.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Gigabyte Computer Sleep Suspend Under Manjaro</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/gigabyte-computer-sleep-suspend-under-manjaro/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 12:08:23 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/gigabyte-computer-sleep-suspend-under-manjaro/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I had configured Manjaro under an old system and was never pressed with the issue of suspend on that old hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Gigabyte computer was finally up and running, I noticed that the system was unable to suspend or sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After failing to find a quick solution to the problem on the archlinux forums, I came across this post from the Manjaro site: &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/manjaro-not-waking-from-suspend-or-sleep/492&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manjaro not waking from suspend or sleep&lt;/a&gt; and I almost knew  - not right away - that the discussion was the underlying cause of the problems I was experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the users, by the handle of &lt;em&gt;artoo&lt;/em&gt; offered to downgrade the kernel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/2017-05-22-artoo-downgrade-suggestion.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kernel number and the year of the post were no longer relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But instead of the solution offered by the user &lt;strong&gt;artoo&lt;/strong&gt; in downgrading, I chose to upgrade instead, especially after the reply by another user who said that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its likeley the problem with hooks in mkinitcpio.conf and users having to
manually mkinitcpio -p linux. Its a weekeley problem on irc and this fixes most
oftenly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its very likely I assumed the initramfs get rebuild one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/2017-05-22-ivan-reply-mkinitcpiio.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the anecdote example almost a month later by another user in which he said that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time execution of mkinitcpio -p linux46 turns out to be sufficient&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./Gigabyte computer sleep suspend under Manjaro · blog del tecnólogo_files/2017-05-22-fordprefect-suggestion-mkinitcpio.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Firefox Problem With Xclip</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/firefox-problem-with-xclip/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 13:58:18 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/firefox-problem-with-xclip/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve used both vim and neovim editors. The latter is just the newest implementation with out of the box pre-configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, whenever I was trying to use the copy paste command tool such as &lt;code&gt;xclip&lt;/code&gt;, both vim and neovim produced the newlines on the X window system across different applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I set out to write an email on Gmail from Alphabet Inc., using a copy paste command tool such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/astrand/xclip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;xclip&lt;/a&gt;, the process was to no avail: newlines were not being displayed on Gmail’s interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closest match was a 2016 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/neovim/neovim/issues/4501&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yanking to clipboard does not preserve newlines (when pasting to some applications&lt;/a&gt; issue that was opened but was eventually closed because the user decided to have &lt;code&gt;xsel&lt;/code&gt; take care of the problem for him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that post raised more questions than answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a reference on that thread about seeing a post on unix.stackexchange.com:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/164074/pasting-in-thunderbird-turns-line-breaks-into-spaces&#34;&gt;http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/164074/pasting-in-thunderbird-turns-line-breaks-into-spaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the link provided, I recall having come across the same post hours earlier when I was trying to find out more about the issue. A Google search with keywords including but not limited to &lt;strong&gt;xclip&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;newlines&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;gmail&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;firefox&lt;/strong&gt; would return as one of the first results, that specific post which appeared on the stackexchange network before any other post and more relevant results would showed up. Perhaps even those that were more important queries on the web were relegated, but I guess that’s an entirely different issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer that was accepted on the stackexchange network for that particular question did nothing to resolve the problem, and I guess it wasn’t until I came across the outstanding bugs on Firefox as I will show later, that the buried comment by a user name Volker Siegel was more relevant than I thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. I indeed was using html. Turning this off solved the problem. What could
be an explanation for that? – user2820379 Apr 28 ‘15 at 8:18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explanation? “Thunderbird, a software that has evolved over more than a decade
to follow changes in protocols and UI expectations. Under these circumstances,
it is inevitable that the structure degrades - know as bit rot. In this
context, it is hard to introduce a new feature in conflict with the current
state, when solving the conflict is infeasible. A new UI feature like HTML
editing may need to be sneaked in between rotten skeletons of old protocol
layers. It will work nicely, but as a result, you will find the configuration
of the new feature down between these old rotten sediments.” – Volker Siegel
Apr 28 ‘15 at 15:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get at the reasoning behind this fiasco and whether to blame neovim or gmail for it.
On vim: pasting worked under the Gmail’s interface, whereas with neovim the process just failed: newlines turned into whitespace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bug is one of those outstanding and hence unresolved that for years has plagued the Firefox browser and its counterpart such as Firebird:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/firefox_bug_newlines.png&#34; alt=&#34;Paste in content editable div from xclip removes newlines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1049785&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paste in contentEditable div from xclip removes newlines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above post made a reference to &lt;a href=&#34;https://productforums.google.com/forum/#!msg/gmail/aV8bdPFiR24/3Owwd9rSaD0J&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gmail ignoring newlines on Copy/Paste&lt;/a&gt; and the unhelpful answer of a user did nothing to pinpoint at the problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/gmail_ignoring_newlines_copypaste.png&#34; alt=&#34;gmail ignoring newlines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ludicrous implementation of &lt;code&gt;\r&lt;/code&gt; before &lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt; is just nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it also does not matter whether &lt;code&gt;printf&lt;/code&gt; was used instead or a simple &lt;code&gt;echo&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ echo -e &#39;una prueba\npara ver&#39; | xclip -sel c 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ echo $&#39;una prueba\npara ver&#39; | xclip -sel c 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;code&gt;xsel&lt;/code&gt; the flags are entirely different. But this clearly showed that Firefox is still trying to catch up with it. Gmail is not the problem. If it were I’d be more than happy to denote it. One could verify it by using a different email service such as Outlook from Microsoft for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick search related to Firefox turned out many more issues than what was originally intended, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1174452&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Copying text with the style “white-space: pre;” does not preserve white space (spaces, tabs, newlines)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the above thread, an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bug1174452.bmoattachments.org/attachment.cgi?id=8646518&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;attachment&lt;/a&gt; provided can also be verified with &lt;code&gt;xclip&lt;/code&gt;. It does not work under Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another &lt;a href=&#34;https://kb.iu.edu/d/bdkf&#34;&gt;bug 116083&lt;/a&gt; is still on the database for the Indiana University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://specifications.freedesktop.org/clipboards-spec/clipboards-latest.txt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clipboard specifications from freedesktop.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Libreoffice Implementación Del Guión en La Separación Silábica</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/libreoffice-implementaci%C3%B3n-del-gui%C3%B3n-en-la-separaci%C3%B3n-sil%C3%A1bica/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 02:29:35 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/libreoffice-implementaci%C3%B3n-del-gui%C3%B3n-en-la-separaci%C3%B3n-sil%C3%A1bica/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Para implementar la separación silábica en cualquier documento en Libreoffice, es necesario bajar los correspondientes archivos de extensiones para este programa: &lt;a href=&#34;https://extensions.libreoffice.org/extensions/spanish-dictionaries/0.6&#34;&gt;https://extensions.libreoffice.org/extensions/spanish-dictionaries/0.6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/libreoffice-download-dictionaries.png&#34; alt=&#34;Diccionario en español con separación silábica y corrector ortográfico&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una vez descargado y guardado este archivo, se utiliza el mismo programa Libreoffice para cargarlo posteriormente.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Después se selecciona bajo el menú de &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt;, y &lt;strong&gt;options&lt;/strong&gt; como se muestra:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/libreoffice-tools-options-menu.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;que por consiguiente inicia la ventana correspondiente que especifica el recién bajado diccionario y como muestra la siguiente figura:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/libreoffice-language-settings.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muy importante en darle clic a &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt; a esta ventana donde el diccionario haya sido seleccionado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Después de esto, y para que el corrector ortográfico aplique al actual documento, es necesario en asegurarnos que el idioma sea seleccionado desde el menú de &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt; seguido de &lt;strong&gt;language&lt;/strong&gt;, y después como opción si el corrector ortográfico se aplicaría a todo el texto del documento, o a solamente un párrafo, y hasta una determinada selección, y como se muestra en la siguiente imagen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/libreoffice-language-selection.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el caso del guión de separación silábica sería necesario en darle clic nuevamente al menú de &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt; (herramientas) seguido de &lt;strong&gt;language&lt;/strong&gt; para que la opción &lt;strong&gt;hyphenation&lt;/strong&gt; tome vigencia y aplique al texto del documento:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/libreoffice-hyphenation-menu-clic.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lo que sucede con el paso anterior, que sencillamente no es lo más práctico. Y lo mismo se puede comprobar si en cada modificación o mejor dicho, en cada terminación de línea o párrafo u oración se tuviese que emplear lo antedicho para que el ingreso automático de guión ocurra a través de todo el texto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para lograr esto, es decir, en emplear en ese caso un ingreso automático del guión silábico, es necesario en ir al menú de &lt;strong&gt;Styles&lt;/strong&gt; seguido de &lt;strong&gt;Styles and Formatting&lt;/strong&gt; del documento como tal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/libreoffice-styles-formatting-menu.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O si te es más fácil dándole clic a &lt;strong&gt;Edit Style&lt;/strong&gt; del actual documento:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/libreoffice-styles-edit-style.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El cual abrirá otra ventana que manipula los valores para la pre-configuración del estilo del documento. Asegúrate que selecciones &lt;strong&gt;Text Flow&lt;/strong&gt; el cual especifica si la &lt;strong&gt;hyphenation&lt;/strong&gt; o la separación silábica ocurriría automáticamente:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/libreoffice-automatic-hyphenation.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una vez que esta opción sea seleccionada, dale a clic para que los cambios apliquen al documento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siempre es aconsejable consultar muchas de las oficiales referencias acerca de este programa en &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.libreoffice.org/&#34;&gt;https://help.libreoffice.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referencia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.libreoffice.org/3.5/Writer/Hyphenation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Libreoffice Help - hyphenation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Gigabyte Motherboard Fails to Load Live Cd but Succeeds With Flash Drive</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/gigabyte-motherboard-fails-to-load-live-cd-but-succeeds-with-flash-drive/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 13:10:35 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/gigabyte-motherboard-fails-to-load-live-cd-but-succeeds-with-flash-drive/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I can’t say whether some of the systems that NUC Intel produces, face the same problems while loading a LiveCD/LiveDVD iso image via an external drive, as the manufacturer Gigabyte currently does. The latter manufacturer gave me the proverbial run for the money when I wanted to install an image that was burned on a DVD and had been successfully installed on an old system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only I tried to load two (2) different images that proved to have been installed without issues and worked correctly on two (2) separate old Dell systems, but it seemed that even after specifying the external DVD/Writer on the first prioritized boot order of the BIOS, the motherboard was simply unable to identify it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t attest whether the BIOS for that particular model is used across similar boards, although is unlikely, but what I can guarantee is that after several attempts, including and not limited to one instance, in which the board seemed to boot in the desired order, in the end was a total disaster: even a warning came up - something that had to do with a missing file from the installation burned DVD image- which appeared on the screen, and would not let me continue.&lt;br&gt;
I wondered at that point whether the motherboard BIOS was clearly identifying the external DVD writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick search on Google confirmed it. The motherboard would identify the external DVD only sparingly and inconsistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an HDD preloaded with an operating system. And had no problems whatsoever to load it directly. But connecting an HDD with a preloaded OS would miss the point altogether. How about if the HDD had no OS preconfigured on it. Then it would become a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Google search returned different scenarios which were not applicable to my situation.
One user pointed out that by disconnecting and connecting the external DVD right after powering on the motherboard resolved his issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone on the Anandtech forums - I remember this website from years before, it published some if not the best reviews about SDDs on the marked - briefly spoke about it. This time around someone on the forum, a subdomain of Anandtech, responded that one reason he/she likes to read the posts is too help him/her determine what motherboard &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to buy. Another user rightfully expressed his dissatisfaction with this particular brand’s issue on modern times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A post on a blog from blogspot pointed out that the solution in his/her case was to tweak with the USB connection. Other responses that followed had to do with the failure on the users’ part, in properly identifying the boot order for the device. But this was not the problem I was having. If anything, I noticed - like I wrote earlier - the inconsistency of the board’s BIOS in simply recognizing the connection. Whereas sometimes it would show right after powering the system, other times it would not show up at all. &lt;a href=&#34;#blogspot&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;blogref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disabling &lt;strong&gt;AHCI&lt;/strong&gt; mode in favor of &lt;strong&gt;Legacy&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;IDE&lt;/strong&gt; like a user pointed out on Anandtech did not resolve it either. And much less by changing the preloaded configuration for &lt;strong&gt;CSM&lt;/strong&gt;. At one point, the system could not even access the BIOS at all, and it became unresponsive. Only after unplugging the cable from the external DVD writer, the BIOS utility would actually show up. This last inconsistent behavior I noticed it by messing with different settings like the ones I mentioned earlier, in which I was faced with the same problem. The only way to access the BIOS was by unplugging the cable. &lt;a href=&#34;#anand&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;anandref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to that point I stopped looking and reading for viable solutions altogether. Nothing I tried seemed to work, even though I could plug in an HDD with a preloaded OS. The GB-BXBT run fine or without major problems on a preloaded OS, and yet I was unable to load a live CD/DVD and install it from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that the problem with the USB for the BIOS settings for example, was supposedly patched years ago. And the latest updates for the BIOS on that particular system occurred a year or two before the manufacturer shipped the system to resellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the external DVD writer would appear and disappear at times while turning on the motherboard was simply beyond me. I was unable to confirm nonetheless the same findings than the user at blogspot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that moment I realized I could no longer waste any more time in trying to install the Live CD/DVD from the DVD writer onto the HDD. Luckily I had an old USB drive lying around that I could use for testing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years I had installed from Live CD/DVDs onto the majority of the systems. It seemed, this was no longer possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to use the simplest method to have a portable OS on a flash drive that could - hopefully install onto the HDD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Arch Wiki &lt;a href=&#34;#dd&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;ddref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the command line could come handy for this purpose:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dd bs=4M if=/path/to/archlinux.iso of=/dev/sdx status=progress &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sync
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a few minutes for the process to finish but in the end I could no longer complain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had to press the &lt;code&gt;DEL&lt;/code&gt; key one more time to access the BIOS. Then just like before, went to specify the boot order that the board should recognize first. The boot sequence showed the HDD on the first spot, followed by the flash drive I had recently copied the image to. Rebooted the system and finally the Manjaro installer loaded without an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation finished without problems. Later I removed the flash drive. Rebooted the system without having to go into the BIOS again., and successfully the fresh installation of Manjaro with the XFCE environment was running updates as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;blogspot&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chromasoft.blogspot.com/2010/10/solving-dreaded-gigabyte-wont-boot-from.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;solving &lt;em&gt;gigabyte wont boot from USB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#blogref&#34;&gt;&amp;crarr;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;anand&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.anandtech.com/threads/dreaded-wont-boot-from-cd-problem-gigabyte-mb-stumped-and-in-need-of-help.2400256&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Anandtech - Won’t boot from CD Gigabyte at Anandtech&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;#anandref&#34;&gt;&amp;crarr;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/USB_flash_installation_media#Using_dd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;USB Flash installation media at Arch Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;dd&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/USB_flash_installation_media#In_GNU.2FLinux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;USB Installation in GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ddref&#34;&gt; ↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Manjaro Desplaza a Ubuntu</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-desplaza-a-ubuntu/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 13:23:51 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-desplaza-a-ubuntu/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hace más o menos un mes que escribí acerca de la configuración del &lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/manjaro-splash-screen-in-ssd/&#34;&gt;tema splash de la pantalla&lt;/a&gt; y el cual se podía anular en la susodicha configuración a través de las &lt;strong&gt;preferencias&lt;/strong&gt;,  seguido del &lt;strong&gt;tema del escritorio&lt;/strong&gt; cuando se utiliza un disco de estado sólido o un SSD (solid state drive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el momento de escribir acerca de ello, y de acuerdo a las estadísticas que se mostraban en &lt;a href=&#34;http://distrowatch.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;distrowatch.com&lt;/a&gt;, los datos que se habían recopilado no reflejaban aún los últimos seis meses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No obstante a ello, es sorprendente que por primera vez en la historia de los sistemas GNU/Linux, una distribución basada en &lt;a href=&#34;https://archlinux.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;  haya dejado rezagadas a distribuciones tales como Opensuse, y más sorprendente aún a Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/gnulinux_ranking_2017.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ranking in the last 6 months&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¿Cuáles han sido (entre varias causas) los más significantes problemas que sistemas tales como Ubuntu han experimentado?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He leído desde hace tiempo la insatisfacción de los usuarios cuando se refiere a la decisión que tomó Canonical en implementar Amazon en el entorno de escritorio Unity. A punto tal que si no hubiese sido por la presión ejercida por muchos de sus usuarios y hasta un artículo de Stallman quien profundizó más acerca de esto en un artículo titulado &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/ubuntu-spyware.en.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ubuntu Spyware: What to do?&lt;/a&gt; donde criticó a este proyecto, el código que Canonical empleó desde el entorno gráfico del gestor de archivos, se continuaría lanzando en cada versión futura.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aparentemente, en la versión 16.04 de LTS (Long Term Support) de Ubuntu, esta función no estaría activada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pero no creo tampoco que estos han sido los problemas más fundamentales que esta distribución experimentó. Los problemas más agudos han sido las propias experimentaciones que los desarrolladores han llevado a cabo con las actualizaciones, las que han causado graves interrupciones que como consecuencia han resultado en sistemas operativos GNU/Linux inservibles e inoperables en muchos de los casos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fui uno de los usuarios, que por ejemplo, experimentó que de buenas a primeras el network-manager crashed. Cuando quise averiguar más tarde, si alguien más estaba atravesando por ello, una búsqueda rápida en Google me redirigió a &lt;a href=&#34;https://askubuntu.com/questions/727127/last-upgrade-crashes-network-manager-no-internet-connection-no-applet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Last upgrade crashes network manager (no internet connection, no applet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Este suceso ejemplifica la descentralización de una distribución cuando toma decisiones reprochables e injustificables. También ejemplifica la irremediable desvinculación de los programadores con una de las distribuciones más user-friendly de todos los tiempos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recuerdo haber leído a Eric Raymond cuando habla sobre este fenómeno en la edificación de una catedral en comparación con un bazar. Considero que fue el primero de estos que el limitado grupo de programadores en Canonical llevó a cabo, en vez de tener en cuenta al usuario, o las acciones que perjudicarían a estos, como medio para el fin y no como un fin por sí solo o para simplemente satisfacer un objetivo sin evaluar profundamente las consecuencias resultantes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si aprenden o no la lección eso pasa a la historia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Configurar El Idioma en Manjaro Kde</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/configurar-el-idioma-en-manjaro-kde/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 12:44:42 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/configurar-el-idioma-en-manjaro-kde/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Para modificar el idioma que los elementos del menú muestren, al igual que el idioma con el que aparecería la hora, la fecha, y otros valores como los de la representación monetaria, se puede ir hasta las &lt;strong&gt;preferencias del sistema&lt;/strong&gt; y después dándole a clic a &lt;strong&gt;Configuración regional&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/modify-regional-language-spanish-manjaro-kde.png&#34; alt=&#34;regional-language-spanish&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La ventana siguiente que lleva de título &lt;strong&gt;añadir y configurar la configuración regional&lt;/strong&gt;, muestra las configuraciones regionales del sistema que  te permite (a mano derecha) añadir el otro idioma que deseas, a la pre-configurada lista de las regiones en el sistema. Debes notar también que una vez que esto sea especificado, el sistema requiere recomenzar para que los cambios se carguen adecuadamente en el sistema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/modify-regional-language-spanish-manjaro-kde-add.png&#34; alt=&#34;regional-language-manjaro-add&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por supuesto que es posible lograr esto mediante el intérprete de comandos a través de &lt;code&gt;localect&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;según se muestra reflejado en &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/locale&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;wiki.archlinux.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es decir,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; localectl set-locale LANG=es_US.UTF 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para ver la lista de los locales en tu sistema, puedes emplear en este caso el siguiente comando:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; localectl list-locales 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;y de ahí seleccionaer el idioma regional que quisieras utilizar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;una vez logrado este paso, es necesario ingresar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;localectl set-locale LANG=es_US.UTF-8 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o el idioma de tu preferencia. Pongo ese solamente como un ejemplo donde se vea ente procedimiento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es bueno recalcar y como lo explica el sitio en &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/locale#Setting_the_system_locale&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;wiki.archlinux.org&lt;/a&gt; que el fichero &lt;code&gt;/etc/locale.gen&lt;/code&gt; muestra aquellas variables que se encuentran señaladas y que posteriormente serían cargadas en el fichero del sistema &lt;code&gt;/etc/locale.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para más información acerca de esto vea la sección &lt;strong&gt;Setting the system locale&lt;/strong&gt; en la wiki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referencias&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;wiki.archlinux.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Pantalla en Reposo Con Manjaro KDE</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/pantalla-en-reposo-con-manjaro-kde/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 13:45:58 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/pantalla-en-reposo-con-manjaro-kde/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Cada vez que se trabaja con algún entorno gráfico en los sistemas GNU/Linux, como GNOME, xfce, MATE, al igual que en KDE, uno se pone al amparo de los desarrolladores de estos sistemas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digo al amparo, porque uno tiene que estar a esperas de lo que estos programadores decidan sobre las configuraciones idóneas del sistema. Y muchas veces, como es de esperar y se ha comprobado a través del tiempo, no han sido las más eficientes decisiones, desde el punto de vista del usuario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si se le pregunta al usuario cuáles serían las mejores maneras para tener acceso a estos servicios gráficos, muchos quizás darían diferentes opiniones. Unos dirían que el lugar en el menú para especificas estas opciones, se encontraría en las &lt;strong&gt;preferencias del sistema&lt;/strong&gt; por ejemplo, mientras que otros posiblemente opinarían que aunque estarían de acuerdo en ello, lo conveniente es resumirlo dentro de la &lt;strong&gt;gestión de energía&lt;/strong&gt; (administración del consumo de energía).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En mi caso, fue la última de estas opciones en las que pensé que cualquier cambio de las configuraciones tomarían lugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pero lo mismo da, en estos casos, porque cuando se han implementado ciertas funciones, la opinión de los usuarios, a no ser aquellas que en esos casos donde por petición popular de la mayoría, logren en acordar y convencer a los desarrolladores en implementarlas, casi siempre no suscitan el interés que otras funciones conllevan. Y por lo tanto estas otras opciones gráficas dejan de ser modificadas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;También hay que tener en cuenta que muchos otros usuarios hispano-parlantes, (o debería decir la gran mayoría), se adaptan a estas condiciones, incluso en aquellos casos donde estas funciones interceden en el uso diario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Este es el caso de algo tan sencillo como el &lt;em&gt;reposo automático de la pantalla&lt;/em&gt; que se experimenta en Manjaro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por norma, el tiempo que transcurre antes que el sistema cierra la sesión, o por lo menos en Manjaro KDE, es de unos cinco minutos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pensé en realizar el cambio desde un principio a través de la ya mencionada &lt;strong&gt;administración del consumo de energía&lt;/strong&gt; o la &lt;strong&gt;gestión de energía&lt;/strong&gt;, pero esta función del sistema no tiene nada que ver con ello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Este reposo de la pantalla, se controla desde &lt;strong&gt;Bloqueo de pantalla&lt;/strong&gt; o &lt;strong&gt;Screen locking&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primero antes que todo, y desde la ventana principal de las &lt;strong&gt;Preferencias del sistema&lt;/strong&gt;, se le da clic al ya mencionado &lt;strong&gt;Comportamiento del escritorio&lt;/strong&gt; (que aparece bajo &lt;strong&gt;Espacio de trabajo&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/comportamiento-del-escritorio-manjaro.png&#34; alt=&#34;comportamiento-del-escritorio&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acto seguido a ello y a mano izquierda, se le da clic a &lt;strong&gt;Bloqueo de pantalla&lt;/strong&gt;, que una vez abre a mano derecha las opciones de configuración bajo el título de &lt;strong&gt;Tiempos de espera del bloqueo de pantalla&lt;/strong&gt; y como se muestra en la siguiente imagen que muestra el tabulador de activación, el período de tiempo en minutos que se necesita modificar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El valor pre-configurado son de unos 5 minutos. Se puede especificar el tiempo que uno estime apropiado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/bloqueo-de-pantalla-screen-locking-manjaro.png&#34; alt=&#34;bloqueo-de-pantalla-en-manjaro&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Turn Off Manjaro Kde Splash Screen if on Ssd</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/turn-off-manjaro-kde-splash-screen-if-on-ssd/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 04:02:19 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/turn-off-manjaro-kde-splash-screen-if-on-ssd/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Posicionado desde hace meses en el quinto escalafón de la lista de las distribuciones basadas en &lt;a href=&#34;http://distrowatch.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;, la distribución &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manjaro &lt;/a&gt;, basada en la impresionante distribución &lt;a href=&#34;http://archlinux.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;, y que hace uso del magnífico sistema de administración de paquetes &lt;strong&gt;Pacman&lt;/strong&gt; de este último, emplea los últimos e innovadores temas de interfaz gráficos en muchas de las ediciones, tanto de la comunidad, como aquellas que son aprobadas oficialmente. &lt;a href=&#34;#man&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;manref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No tuve problema alguno con la instalación del sistema operativo. Todo parecía funcionar sin problemas. La tarjeta gráfica del ordenador se había identificado apropiadamente durante el proceso de instalación, al igual que la tarjeta inalámbrica que permite el acceso al Internet para la continuación de cualquier actualización que se necesitaría llevar a cabo más tarde.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El mayor problema recaía en el tiempo que tomaba antes que el escritorio gráfico de este sistema operativo estuviera disponible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Después de reinicializar las sesiones en varias ocasiones, me di cuenta que este lapso que estaba experimentando, no era algo necesariamente deseable, y peor aún, porque muchas veces fallaba por completo en cargar el entorno gráfico KDE, mientras que el resto del sistema estaba simplemente congelado. Esto imposibilitaba por ende, el acceso a la línea de intérprete de comandos, al igual que a cualquier operación de revisión de errores. Bajo estas condiciones, el sistema entero se paralizaba y por consiguiente era algo inaceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aunque el origen de este problema no era tan sencillo de rastrear, me di cuenta que ‘startx’ podía ser el causante. Una búsqueda rápida en Google dio como resultados en su primer hit de búsqueda a una pregunta similar titulada: &lt;em&gt;Plasma desktop 5 boots very slowly&lt;/em&gt; que había sido hecha en el boletín de Arch Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La pregunta del op era la siguiente:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is there any way to debug Plasma-desktop 5 loading process to figure out why it is slow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a lo que una respuesta continuaba después que decía:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if on ssd, it’s better to turn off splash screen. &lt;a href=&#34;#ssd&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;ssdref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y eso era exactamente lo que estaba ocurriendo, o por lo menos en mi caso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Después de ello y una vez en el menú gráfico del sistema, se selecciona las configuraciones del sistema o &lt;em&gt;settings&lt;/em&gt; . Una vez allí y bajo el tabulador &lt;em&gt;Appearance&lt;/em&gt; se selecciona &lt;em&gt;Workspace Theme&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/manjaro-workspace.png&#34; alt=&#34;manjaro-workspace&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/tema-del-espacio-de-trabajo.png&#34; alt=&#34;manjaro-espacio-de-trabajo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una vez que se seleccione el &lt;em&gt;Tema&lt;/em&gt; y como se mostrará en la siguiente figura, se debe especificar que &lt;em&gt;None&lt;/em&gt; o &lt;em&gt;ninguno&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/manjaro-splash.png&#34; alt=&#34;manjaro-splash&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/no-splash-en-manjaro-kde.png&#34; alt=&#34;manjaro-no-splash&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Footnotes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;man&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/get-manjaro/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lanzamientos oficiales de Manjaro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#manref&#34;&gt;&amp;crarr;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;ssd&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sugerencia de un usuario en ajustar el valor pre-configurado del espacio de trabajo. Para más información acerca de ello visite el siguiente sitio que ofrece más detalles acerca de la conversación &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?pid=1557789#p1557789&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;turn off splash if on ssd&#34;&gt;turn off splash if on ssd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ssdref&#34;&gt; ↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Reemplazo De Minúsculas Con Mayúsculas Con Emacs</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/reemplazo-de-min%C3%BAsculas-con-may%C3%BAsculas-con-emacs/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 02:31:55 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/reemplazo-de-min%C3%BAsculas-con-may%C3%BAsculas-con-emacs/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Para un simple reemplazo de caracteres al principio de una oración, es decir, de minúsculas por mayúsculas, se puede emplear un simple y eficiente método de expresión regular también en Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ya existe un modo de &lt;em&gt;capitalization&lt;/em&gt; que logra este reemplazo de una cadena de caracteres o cadena de texto como se dice en inglés: string, y aunque tiene un inigualable mérito para este propósito, de igual manera retrasa el ingreso de caracteres., como es de esperar, el retraso o el lapso que esto conlleva, es una desventaja para una óptima funcionalidad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digamos por ejemplo que:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;foo bar. foo bar. foo bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para modificar la minúscula por una mayúscula:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; M-x replace-regex
 \(\. \w\)
 \,(capitalize \1)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;que nos da como resultado:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;foo bar. Foo bar. Foo bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pero el comienzo de la oración o de la línea no se ha modificado, entonces:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; M-x replace-regex
 \(^\w\)
 \,(capitalize \1)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;logra hacer la modificación restante a:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foo bar. Foo bar. Foo bar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si deseas hacer la modificación de una vez y por todas, y abreviando por consiguiente las dos expresiones regulares anteriores, utilizarías en este caso el delimitador &lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; antes de la barra oblicua &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt;. Es decir:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; M-x replace-regex
 \(^\w\|\. \w\)
 \,(capitalize \1) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reemplaza el original foo bar. foo bar. foo bar. A Foo bar. Foo bar. Foo bar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Reemplazar Con Vim. Reemplazos de minúsculas con mayúsculas</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/reemplazar-con-vim/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 13:48:53 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/reemplazar-con-vim/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;O como se dice en Inglés: &lt;em&gt;capitalization&lt;/em&gt;, se puede lograr fácilmente en &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;vim &lt;/a&gt; mediante el empleo de mayúsculas al comienzo de oraciones a través del uso de una expresión regular o regex, sin la necesidad de utilizar algún que otro script (que puede causar efectos secundarios en el funcionamiento), para lograr el reemplazo de las minúsculas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el website de programadores de superuser.com, &lt;a href=&#34;http://superuser.com/questions/737130/automatically-capitalize-the-first-letter-of-sentence-in-vim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;superuser.com/questions/737130/automatically-capitalize-the-first-letter-of-sentence-in-vim&lt;/a&gt; se hace esta misma pregunta para lograr el reemplazo automático de minúsculas por mayúsculas al principio de cada oración.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una de las repuestas &lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/reemplazo-de-minusculas-por-mayuscula-en-oracion/#script&#34;&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hace énfasis de esto mediante la adición de un unas líneas de script o programa de ejecución.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El problema que esto conlleva, y como uno de los usuarios comentó,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem is this script seems to add a noticeable lag when typing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es que mientras más extenso sea el documento, más se experimenta el lag o el retraso en el ingreso de caracteres. Es decir, la óptima funcionalidad se pierde parcialmente. Solo es necesario en tener un documento que comprenda un número de ciento y algo líneas, (y esto es sin contar que haya encima de ello algunas que otras líneas de código), para notar la diferencia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considero que sin tanta complicación que más tarde nos puede afectar, la mínima utilización de un reemplazo de caracteres mediante una expresión regular, tuviese mejores resultados.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para cambiar la minúscula por mayúscula sería necesario entonces algo como:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ :%s/\.[a-z]/\U&amp;amp;/g
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e. g.,  si el espacio después de la puntuación fue ingresado, no se te olvide cambiar el código encima con el espacio sobrante correspondiente, tal como&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ :%s/\. [a-z]/\U&amp;amp;/g
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;y para lograr el intercambio al comienzo de cada línea, entonces&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ :%s/^[a-z]/\U&amp;amp;/g
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reemplaza la minúscula desde el comienzo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para reemplazar múltiples patrones de búsqueda, se debe emplear el sufijo &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; después de la expresión regular con la que se modificaría la búsqueda,  separado de una barra vertical &lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; que separe los dos grupos, es decir:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ :%s/^[a-z]/\U&amp;amp;/ge | %s/\. [a-z]/\U&amp;amp;/ge
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otras de las maneras de emplear esta &lt;em&gt;expresión regular&lt;/em&gt; es mediante la substitución de &lt;code&gt;[a-z]&lt;/code&gt; por &lt;code&gt;\w&lt;/code&gt;. una búsqueda rápida en &lt;code&gt;:help&lt;/code&gt; nos indica que &lt;code&gt;\w&lt;/code&gt; equivale a &lt;code&gt;[0-9A-Za-z]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;por lo tanto se pudiese emplear algo tal como&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ :%s/^\w/\U&amp;amp;/ge | %s/\. \w/\U&amp;amp;/ge 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Footnotes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/post/reemplazo-de-minusculas-por-mayuscula-en-oracion/#fnref&#34;&gt; ↩︎&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a name=&#34;script&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Respuesta de usuario de vim para el empleo de un script que reemplace minúscula por mayúscula pero que causa lag en documentos &lt;a href=&#34;http://superuser.com/a/737155&#34;&gt;http://superuser.com/a/737155&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Modificar Mapa Del Teclado Con Emacs Y Vim</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/modificar-mapa-del-teclado-con-emacs-y-vim/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 14:40:45 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/modificar-mapa-del-teclado-con-emacs-y-vim/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Estos son algunos de los ejemplos que se pueden utilizar a través de los inmensamente populares editores de programación Emacs &lt;a href=&#34;#emacs&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; y Vim &lt;a href=&#34;#vim&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, para cambiar el mapa del teclado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;emacs&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El altamente configurable y extensible editor de texto Emacs también nos puede ayudar con modificaciones del teclado, o cambiar la localización de las teclas, sin la necesidad de cambiar todo el diseño, y sin la necesidad de tener que utilizar algún teclado en específico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primero se crea una función que se le asigna un nombre determinado. En este caso utilizamos el nombre de “backslash”. Posteriormente a esto, se le atribuye el comando &lt;code&gt;insert&lt;/code&gt; seguido de &lt;code&gt;kbd&lt;/code&gt; y el mapa del registro del teclado que se desea modificar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En mi caso, encontré conveniente intercambiar las teclas &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt; por &lt;code&gt;;&lt;/code&gt; y viceversa. Por ejemplo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defun backslash ()
  (interactive)
  (insert (kbd &#34;\\&#34;)))

(global-set-key (kbd &#34;; &#34; ) &#39;backslash)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;al igual que:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defun semicolon ()
  (interactive)
  (insert (kbd &#34;;&#34; )))

(global-set-key (kbd &#34;\\&#34; ) &#39;semicolon)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Como se puede ver en los ejemplos anteriores, después de esto se le asigna &lt;code&gt;global-set-key&lt;/code&gt; a la recién nombrada función. Es decir, en el primer caso, la función se le asignó el nombre &lt;code&gt;backslash&lt;/code&gt;, y la cual fue directamente entrelazada con el ya mencionado comando &lt;code&gt;global-set-key&lt;/code&gt; seguido de la tecla &lt;code&gt;;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;De esta manera se logra el objetivo deseado. Esto es, que el ingreso de una tecla dada en el mapa del teclado del registro de entrada del sistema operativo, sea interpretado  posteriormente, - mediante la nueva asignación que proveyó la función - con el registro del mapa de otra tecla que haya sido predeterminada, dando lugar con ello a que ese ingreso del mapa del teclado, se registre apropiadamente con los resultados de la salida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el primer ejemplo, cada vez que la tecla &lt;code&gt;;&lt;/code&gt;sea presionada, la tecla &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt; tomará precedencia. Y viceversa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vim&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;en el caso de Vim, el editor de texto más utilizado en Unix, y el cual está disponible de fábrica, o en la mayoría de las variaciones de Unix, el modificar el mapa del teclado se obtiene de varias maneras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solamente mostraré el comando que lograría esto de la manera más simple y durante el modo de insertar: &lt;code&gt;inoremap&lt;/code&gt;, el cual es seguido de la tecla que se desea modificar, con la que tomaría la nueva posición.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es decir:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; inoremap ; \
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lograría lo que en este caso se quisiera. Cada vez que la tecla &lt;code&gt;;&lt;/code&gt; se presione, la &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt; tomará su lugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;De la misma manera, cuando se especifica el anterior comando en el fichero de inicialización, conlleva a especificar el mismo comando, es decir &lt;code&gt;inoremap&lt;/code&gt; pero en esta ocasión con los símbolos de manera inversa. De otra manera, ambas teclas tendrán asignadas el mismo mapa en el registro del teclado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por lo tanto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;inoremap \ ; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sería imprescindible para finalizar la modificación de estas teclas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Reemplazos en Vim</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/reemplazos-en-vim/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 14:42:55 -0500</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/reemplazos-en-vim/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Estos son algunos de los reemplazos que se pudieran realizar en vim:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:s/\zs/\r/g
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will have this string of characters: abcdefghi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tendrá esta cadena de caracteres: abcdefghi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;result&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a&lt;br&gt;
b&lt;br&gt;
c&lt;br&gt;
d&lt;br&gt;
e&lt;br&gt;
f&lt;br&gt;
g&lt;br&gt;
h&lt;br&gt;
i&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por otra parte la siguiente ejecución:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:s/\s/\r/g 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;esto es una prueba&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;result&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;esto&lt;br&gt;
es&lt;br&gt;
una&lt;br&gt;
prueba&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and &lt;code&gt;:s/\n//g&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will have something like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a&lt;br&gt;
b&lt;br&gt;
c&lt;br&gt;
d&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;results&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;abcde&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:s/\n/ /g
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will have something like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;esto&lt;br&gt;
es&lt;br&gt;
una&lt;br&gt;
prueba&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;result&lt;/strong&gt;: esto es una prueba&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;por supuesto, se puede ver que en algunos casos se utiliza &lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt;, mientras que en otros se utiliza &lt;code&gt;\r&lt;/code&gt;, es necesario recordar que en cada reemplazo y substitución en vim, se logra mediante &lt;code&gt;:s/texto para reemplazar/substituir con&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primero antes que todo el delimitador de barra oblicua &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; es la separación de lo que se quiere modificar con lo que se modificaría.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es decir, por ejemplo, donde &lt;code&gt;texto para reemplazar&lt;/code&gt; es la expresión regular que se desea cambiar, o los caracteres del texto que se desean modificar, mientras que &lt;code&gt;substituir con&lt;/code&gt; es el nuevo ingreso que tomará lugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En este caso, para entender este procedimiento, no hay mejor ayuda en vim, que ir directo a la documentación con &lt;code&gt;:help \n&lt;/code&gt; o mediante &lt;code&gt;:h \n&lt;/code&gt; para abreviar, y también entender el por qué difiere de &lt;code&gt;:help \r&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creo que una de las mejores respuestas sobre esto, se encuentra en &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/a/18961239&#34;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/a/18961239&lt;/a&gt; que especifica que “in the syntax &lt;code&gt;s/foo/bar&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;\r&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt; have different meanings depending on context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En nuestro caso sería &lt;code&gt;s/texto para reemplazar/substituir con&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por lo tanto esto equivaldría a:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el caso de &lt;code&gt;texto para reemplazar&lt;/code&gt;, es decir, &lt;code&gt;s/&amp;lt;texto para reemplazar&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; antes del segundo delimitador &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt; sería una newline  o un salto de línea.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;\r&lt;/code&gt; en este caso sería CR que es la tecla &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;, tecla de retorno o de regreso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el caso de &lt;code&gt;substituir con&lt;/code&gt;, es decir, &lt;code&gt;s/&amp;lt;texto para reemplazar&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;substituir con&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, o los caracteres que se encuentren después de la segunda barra &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt; seria un octeto nulo&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;\r&lt;/code&gt; en este caso es una &lt;code&gt;newline&lt;/code&gt; o un salto de línea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hugo No Sincroniza Directorio Estatico en Github</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/hugo-no-sincroniza-directorio-estatico-en-github/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 10:09:44 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/hugo-no-sincroniza-directorio-estatico-en-github/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Después de realizar varias pruebas donde traté de evaluar algún que otro theme en Hugo, me di cuenta que el problema era más serio que lo pensaba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tenía en mente llevar las pruebas con ciertos temas minimalistas, o como se diría en español: simples, que me permitiesen llevar a cabo flexibles modificaciones locales., y de ahí partir con ello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La mayoría de los temas en Hugo están constituidos por ciertos paquetes de láminas en estilo de cascadas, o con las siglas en inglés por CSS, y al igual que otros pequeños ficheros en Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cabe aclarar que la mayoría, por no decir todos, emplean las últimas tecnologías en gráficos que validen la convención estándar establecida por el consorcio W3C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Les recomiendo a todos aquellos que estén interesados en generadores estáticos del web, que evalúen a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; y de ahí decidir si es o no el motor más eficiente y fiable que hace uso de estas últimas tecnologías. Por supuesto que no sería justo si no se menciona otros como &lt;a href=&#34;https://hexo.io/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;hexo&lt;/a&gt;, desarrollado en Javascript por ejemplo, que al igual que el primero, son motores que valen la pena en emplearlos en la producción de sitios web, en la elaboración de blogs, al igual que con cualquier otra documentación.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El motor &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, fue desarrollado en golang - un lenguaje de programación que fue creado en Google - es uno de los más recientes en este campo de generadores estáticos que ha sido recibido con mucho interés por programadores y otros entusiastas en computación. Pero sobre esto hablaré en otro artículo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Como dije al principio, en esta ocasión me interesaba más la flexible estructuración del blog que más que nada, mediante la evaluación de algunos de los &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;temas&lt;/a&gt; que están disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le había hecho algunos que otros cambios a uno de ellos intitulado purehugo y basado mayormente en &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/bootstrapCDN&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;bootstrapCDN&lt;/a&gt; logré llevar a cabo algunos que otros cambios, me mortificaba la idea que no podía omitir la generación de todos los posts en la raíz del servidor. Por mucho que traté de hacer los cambios, la creación de una página que no sería mostrada en la página principal del servidor, era casi imposible. Tampoco quería emplear más tiempo que el necesario en lograr esto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decidí entonces en descargar una plantilla temática que lleva de nombre &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/shiori/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;shiori&lt;/a&gt;, que fue portado o transferido de la implementación original del tema del mismo nombre por su autor Shusaku Uesugi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estaba tratando de implementar en la estructura de la página un tema sencillo y este susodicho tema mostraba llenar los requisitos para ello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Después de descargarlo en el directorio &lt;code&gt;themes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone https://github.com/chibicode/hugo-theme-shiori shiori
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;decidí en ponerlo en práctica&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo server -t shiori 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;y el servidor local en el ordenador mostraba sin problemas la paginación correcta, al igual que todos los posts. No intenté en llevar otros cambios de modificación, porque la primera vez que ejecuté &lt;code&gt;hugo new post/test&lt;/code&gt; que proseguiría con la creación de un post en el archivo de contenido, un error acerca del fichero &lt;code&gt;archetypes&lt;/code&gt; se había generado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traté de encontrar más información acerca de ello. Pero la única explicación acerca de esto tenía que ver con la actualización no solo de &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; sino de todas las dependencias de este:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;go get -u -v github.com/spf13/hugo
github.com/spf13/hugo (download)
github.com/fsnotify/fsnotify (download)
Fetching https://golang.org/x/sys/unix?go-get=1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El servidor local me mostraba las modificaciones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una búsqueda más tarde en Google me refirió a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/issues/1802&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iHugo 0.16-DEV (Jan 2016) fails to sync theme’s static directory on Linux&lt;/a&gt; el cual trataba este problema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aparentemente una de las dependencias tenía que ser actualizada, y por lo tanto la bandera &lt;code&gt;-u&lt;/code&gt; tenía que ser especificada apropiadamente para la instalación del motor &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Flechas en Gimp</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/flechas-en-gimp/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 14:16:59 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/flechas-en-gimp/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Una de las maneras más fáciles en crear &lt;strong&gt;flechas&lt;/strong&gt; en Gimp, sería con la adición de un plugin al directorio &lt;code&gt;scripts&lt;/code&gt; de Gimp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el sitio de &lt;a href=&#34;https://graphicdesign.stackexchange.com/questions/44797/how-do-i-insert-arrows-into-a-picture-in-gimp&#34;&gt;https://graphicdesign.stackexchange.com/questions/44797/how-do-i-insert-arrows-into-a-picture-in-gimp&lt;/a&gt; se puede encontrar más información en cuanto a esto. Solamente mostraré los pasos visuales para lograrlo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $cd /directorio-de-gimp/scripts/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seguido de&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $wget http://registry.gimp.org/files/arrow.scm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y recomienza el programa Gimp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digamos por ejemplo, que seleccionas un nuevo documento. En la caja de herramientas de Gimp (recuerda que si no está visible, siempre puedes activarla a través de la combinación en el teclado de &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; y &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;), podrás ver la nueva inclusión de la ventana de herramienta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veamos como funciona con la selección de esta misma caja de herramientas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/selecciona-toolbox.png&#34; alt=&#34;caja de herramientas toolbox&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El próximo paso sería seleccionar el icono con el que se marcan los dos puntos de la flecha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/click-twice.png&#34; alt=&#34;clic dos vecs&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asegúrate que el color como se muestra en la figura anterior, esté seleccionado apropiadamente en la caja de herramientas (toolbox).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una vez que los dos puntos hayan sido marcados, selecciona la barra del menú principal de &lt;code&gt;Herramientas/tools&lt;/code&gt;, descendiendo hasta el final y dándole clic a &lt;code&gt;Arrows&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una vez que le des a &lt;code&gt;Arrows&lt;/code&gt; del menú principal de la barra, una ventana que es similar a la que se muestra a continuación te permitirá especificar ciertos valores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/select-tools-arrow.png&#34; alt=&#34;selecciona el menú principal de arrows&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una vez que tengas la ventana abierta, ajusta los valores de porcentajes según el grosor, o el ancho que los ángulos de la flecha debiesen tener cuando se le aplique el color configurado. También puedes especificar otros valores como en rellenar a todo color la punta de la flecha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clic &lt;code&gt;ok&lt;/code&gt; una vez que los valores sean los acordados.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/arrow-done.png&#34; alt=&#34;flecha finalizadai&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Git in Six Hundred Words by Mary Rose Cook</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/git-in-six-hundred-words-by-mary-rose-cook/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 14:45:04 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/git-in-six-hundred-words-by-mary-rose-cook/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have a directory called &lt;code&gt;alpha&lt;/code&gt;. It contains a file called &lt;code&gt;number.txt&lt;/code&gt; that contains the text &lt;code&gt;first&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt; to set up &lt;code&gt;alpha&lt;/code&gt; as a Git repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git add number.txt&lt;/code&gt; to add &lt;code&gt;number.txt&lt;/code&gt; to the index. The index is a list of all the files that Git is keeping track of. It maps filenames to the content of the files. It now has the mapping &lt;code&gt;number.txt -&amp;gt; first&lt;/code&gt;. Running the add command has also added a blob object containing &lt;code&gt;first&lt;/code&gt; to the Git object database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;main __reader_view_article_wrap_4270907014602854__&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;(This essay is a companion piece to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gitlet.maryrosecook.com/&#34;&gt;Gitlet&lt;/a&gt;, my implementation of Git in JavaScript.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have a directory called &lt;code&gt;alpha&lt;/code&gt;. It contains a file called &lt;code&gt;number.txt&lt;/code&gt; that contains the text &lt;code&gt;first&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt; to set up &lt;code&gt;alpha&lt;/code&gt; as a Git repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git add number.txt&lt;/code&gt; to add &lt;code&gt;number.txt&lt;/code&gt; to the index. The index is a list of all the files that Git is keeping track of. It maps filenames to the content of the files. It now has the mapping &lt;code&gt;number.txt -&amp;gt; first&lt;/code&gt;. Running the add command has also added a blob object containing &lt;code&gt;first&lt;/code&gt; to the Git object database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git commit -m first&lt;/code&gt;. This does three things. First, it creates a tree object in the objects database. This object represents the list of items in the top level of the alpha directory. This object has a pointer to the &lt;code&gt;first&lt;/code&gt; blob object that was created when you ran &lt;code&gt;git add&lt;/code&gt;. Second, it creates a commit object that represents the version of the repository that you have just committed. This includes a pointer to the tree object. Third, it points the master branch at the new commit object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git clone . ../beta&lt;/code&gt;. This creates a new directory called &lt;code&gt;beta&lt;/code&gt;. It initializes it as a Git repository. It copies the objects in the alpha objects database to the beta objects database. It points the master branch on beta at the commit object that the master branch points at on the alpha repository. It sets the index on beta to mirror the content of the first commit. It updates your files - &lt;code&gt;number.txt&lt;/code&gt; - to mirror the index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You move to the beta repository. You change the content of &lt;code&gt;number.txt&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;second&lt;/code&gt;. You run &lt;code&gt;git add number.txt&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;git commit -m second&lt;/code&gt;. The commit object that is created has a pointer to its parent, the first commit. The commit command points the master branch at the second commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You move back to the alpha repository. You run &lt;code&gt;git remote add beta ../beta&lt;/code&gt;. This sets the beta repository as a remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git pull beta master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the covers, this runs &lt;code&gt;git fetch beta master&lt;/code&gt;. This finds the objects for the second commit and copies them from the beta repository to the alpha repository. It points alpha’s record of beta’s master at the second commit object. It updates &lt;code&gt;FETCH_HEAD&lt;/code&gt; to show that the master branch was fetched from the beta repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the covers, the pull command runs &lt;code&gt;git merge FETCH_HEAD&lt;/code&gt;. This reads &lt;code&gt;FETCH_HEAD&lt;/code&gt;, which shows that the master branch on the beta repository was the most recently fetched branch. It gets the commit object that alpha’s record of beta’s master is pointing at. This is the second commit. The master branch on alpha is pointing at the first commit, which is the ancestor of the second commit. This means that, to complete the merge, the merge command can just point the master branch at the second commit. The merge command updates the index to mirror the contents of the second commit. It updates the working copy to mirror the index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git branch red&lt;/code&gt;. This creates a branch called &lt;code&gt;red&lt;/code&gt; that points at the second commit object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git checkout red&lt;/code&gt;. Before the checkout, &lt;code&gt;HEAD&lt;/code&gt; pointed at the master branch. It now points at the red branch. This makes the red branch the current branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You set the content of &lt;code&gt;number.txt&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;third&lt;/code&gt;, run &lt;code&gt;git add numbers.txt&lt;/code&gt; and run &lt;code&gt;git commit -m third&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run &lt;code&gt;git push beta red&lt;/code&gt;. This finds the objects for the third commit and copies them from the alpha repository to the beta repository. It points the red branch on the beta repository at the third commit object, and that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If you would like to learn about the internals of Git in detail, you can read my essay, &lt;a href=&#34;https://maryrosecook.com/blog/post/git-from-the-inside-out&#34;&gt;Git from the inside out&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Círculos en Gimp</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/circulos-en-gimp/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 14:13:46 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/circulos-en-gimp/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Esto es solamente un recordatorio para realizar varias modificaciones a cualquier imagen en &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GNU  Gimp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No soy un usuario de este programa, pero reconozco que como manipulador de gráficos e imágenes, es incomparable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hace un tiempo, recuerdo haber leído algo acerca de esto a través del blog de &lt;a href=&#34;http://alvinalexander.com/gimp/gimp-how-to-create-draw-circle-in-gimp-tutorial/&#34;&gt;Alvin Alexander&lt;/a&gt; que toca sobre la creación de círculos, elipses y demás.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Algunos de los pasos los omitiré, porque algunos son innecesarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Primero crea una imagen, un nuevo documento, aunque por supuesto, que puedes abrir cualquier otra imagen &lt;code&gt;png&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;jpeg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;jpg&lt;/code&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Después en la caja de herramienta, selecciona el elipsis que te servirá para demarcar el trazo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/selectelilipse.png&#34; alt=&#34;Selecciona elipse&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dibuja el trazo del círculo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/dibujaimagen.png&#34; alt=&#34;dibuja imagen&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Una vez realizado este círculo, dale a clic al menú de &lt;code&gt;Select&lt;/code&gt;, y desciende hasta que te encuentres con el &lt;code&gt;Border&lt;/code&gt; (borde).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;En la nueva ventana que aparece donde te especifica en seleccionar en pixels la dimensión de este borde, incrementa o disminuye estos pixels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/selectmenuborder.png&#34; alt=&#34;Selecciona el borde del Menú&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asegúrate que el color que tienes seleccionado en la caja de herramientas sea el correcto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clic en el menú de &lt;code&gt;Edit&lt;/code&gt; desde la ventana principal de Gimp y selecciona &lt;code&gt;Fill with FG Color&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/círculocolor.png&#34; alt=&#34;Círculo después de fill with color&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Cambia Tu Contraseña en Gmail Y Google</title>
          <link>https://imfrom.github.io/post/cambia-tu-contrase%C3%B1a-en-gmail-y-google/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 14:48:19 CDT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>https://imfrom.github.io/post/cambia-tu-contrase%C3%B1a-en-gmail-y-google/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Toda la ayuda que se necesite acerca de GMail, y cualquier otro producto de Google, se puede obtener a través de la página de estos en &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/&#34;&gt;https://support.google.com/&lt;/a&gt; pero no obstante a ello, enumeraré algunos que otros pasos para recuperar la contraseña o clave, en caso que se haya extraviado o por cualquier otro motivo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estas son algunas imágenes que se mostrarán, si tienes el idioma seleccionado como Español, o castellano,  en tu navegador.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/111.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Que como se explica en &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/mail/answer/41078?hl=es&#34;&gt;https://support.google.com/mail/answer/41078?hl=es&lt;/a&gt; puedes reiniciar tu sesión para restablecer otra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/7.png&#34; alt=&#34;inicia sesión&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una vez que le des clic te dirigirá hacia un enlace que te preguntará con tres (3) opciones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/555.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;inicio de sesión&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acto seguido a ello, seleccionas una de ellas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por ejemplo, si seleccionas la primera de estas, porque simplemente se te ha olvidado, te da la opción de ingresar el correo electrónico que normalmente utilizas para el inicio de la sesión.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/8.png&#34; alt=&#34;correo de inicio para gmail&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El próximo enlace te preguntará por la última clave que recuerdas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le das clic a &lt;strong&gt;No lo sé&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/444.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;escribe lo que te recuerdas&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Después que ingreses tu correo electrónico, o cualquier otro método de verificación secundario: así sea mediante otro correo electrónico, o mediante SMS de mensaje de texto, que empleaste durante el registro de la cuenta, Google te enviará un enlace, un link, que te permitirá restablecer otra contraseña.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recuerda en clic &lt;strong&gt;Continuar&lt;/strong&gt; para que el proceso comience, o de lo contrario la recuperación de la contraseña no será posible, según las actuales configuraciones que Google emplea para este proceso,  que requiere que se sigan los pasos como se muestra antes que Google te reenvíe otro email que te permita ingresar otra contraseña.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imfrom.github.io/images/99.png&#34; alt=&#34;clic continuar&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si no tienes acceso al método de recuperación que especificaste, aún así, Google te permite verificar tu identidad mediante otras preguntas con respuestas que se utilizaron durante el registro de la cuenta.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
